<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Seo on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/categories/seo/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:00:06 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Tips For Your New Website</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:00:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you launch your brand new website, make sure you take these quick tips into account.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1737&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few tips for your new website, creating a new website can be a lot of work. Between coming up with a design, building the site (or hiring a developer) and marketing the new idea, you’re putting in several hours to ensure that your site will draw in new visitors while keeping the current ones engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you hit these targets  to increase customer engagement with your new website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile-friendly design.&lt;/strong&gt; 64% of Americans now have a smartphone, and most of them are using them to access the internet on a daily basis. Make sure your site is easily accessible and navigable from a mobile device. Not only is it important to create a smooth browsing experience for mobile users, Google now actually penalizes sites that aren’t deemed “mobile friendly”. Make sure mobile-friendly design is at the top of your list. We suggest looking at responsive web design for best results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to action.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t simply want your visitors going to your site, admiring the good design, and leaving. You want them to take action. Make sure you include a strong Call To Action (CTA) on your homepage. Make your CTA obvious and simple to follow. Your visitors should find it easy to sign up for your newsletter, make a purchase or give you feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved usability.&lt;/strong&gt; Your site should be visually appealing, but that counts for nothing if your visitors can’t find their way around your site. Usability is key when trying to keep your visitors on your site. To improve usability, make sure you consider your audience when designing your site. Will they know where to click next? Are you answering their questions? Will they be frustrated with anything on the site? Your visitors will leave right away if they’re confused about your site’s layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less is more.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t go overboard with excessive design. Think about usability first, and then make your site appealing to the eye. By using the right typography for your brand, tying in a consistent color scheme and including images that send the right message, you’re on your way to an effective, user-friendly design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informative ‘About Us’ page.&lt;/strong&gt; Let your visitors know exactly who you are and what kind of values your business has. An ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/what-does-your-about-us-page-really-say/&#34;&gt;About Us’ page should be informative and honest&lt;/a&gt;; people love seeing what really lies at the core of a company. If you’re a well-established business, display some of your accomplishments throughout the years. If you’re an up-and-coming startup, outline some of your goals for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compelling copy.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes back to finding your audience and talking directly to them. Now that someone has arrived at your site, pitch them your message! Copy should sound convincing, but you never want to come off as too salesy or intrusive. Be conversational and provide the answers that they’re searching for (that’s why most people are online – to get answers!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When in doubt, A/B test!&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes there’s no way of knowing which design will perform best. When launching your site, try a few different designs and see which one produces optimal results. This way, there is no doubting which design will work better for your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed up your site.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s almost nothing that will drive away your visitors more quickly than &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/&#34;&gt;slow loading times&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, 40% of people say they will leave a page if it takes longer than 3 seconds to load. Check out this blog post to see how you can easily speed up your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Optimization, An Easy Win For A Faster Site</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/image-optimization-an-easy-win-for-a-faster-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:05:27 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/image-optimization-an-easy-win-for-a-faster-site/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Website speed optimization can be a complex and technical practice, but the non-techies out there will be happy to learn that one of the biggest problems is actually easy for the layperson to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-with-images&#34;&gt;The Problem With Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Optimization, An Easy Win For A Faster Site. Images are typically the one of the biggest drains on page load time. Even with caching and a CDN, an unoptimized image will still drag down your page loading time. But, as the website owner, images are completely under your control, so if you can get a handle on how to work with and optimize images, you can have a great impact on the speed of your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the websites that I look at during my Intispace customer support duties, I see that images contribute, on average, about 30% of the total page load time. Often this is the single largest factor of the loading time. In extreme cases, it could be closer to 60% of the loading time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what un-optimized images will do to your site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-431  lazyautosizes lazyloaded&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/pingdom-image-slow-site.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Large Images slow down your website&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;108&#34; data-lazy-src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/pingdom-image-slow-site.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The load time is 12 seconds and the size of the page is 8MB. Of those 8MB, images account for 6.7MB. This is out of control!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of http requests is commonly cited as a factor in load time, and while it is important, ultimately it’s the page size that is the real indicator of speed or slowness. You can have a small number of http requests, but if those requests are summoning giant images, you will have a problem on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-dimensions-and-file-size&#34;&gt;Understanding Dimensions and File Size&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dimensions of the image, i.e. how much space on the screen an image takes up, are measured in pixels and while they do not 100% dictate file size, they are related. The larger the dimensions of your image, the larger the file size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File size is measured in kilobytes (KB) and megabytes (MB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1MB = 1000KB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a point of reference, the main content column of this blog is 796 pixels wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take a photo with your smartphone, depending on your settings, that photo could be in the region of 2500 pixels wide (or even more) with a filesize of 3MB (or 3000KB). If I were to take a photo with my phone and upload it to this blog without any editing, I’m going to be uploading a file that is about 3 times as big as it needs to be – a total waste of resources and a drag on page load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while snapping phone pics and uploading to your blog might be simple, it creates a real problem if you want a fast site,  by adding tons of unnecessary weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resizing-images&#34;&gt;Resizing Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first thing you need to do is resize your images to the correct size for your site. For blog images, figure out how wide your blog’s content area is  and never upload an image wider than that. If it’s going to be used in a slider, make sure you determine the dimensions of the slider first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you know how wide your content area is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know how to use the developer tools built in to Chrome or Firefox, you can use that. But if that sounds scary there are simpler tools available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on a Mac, there is a screen capture tool, Grab, already built-in, and when you outline an area on the screen it will tell you the pixels. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aeyoun.com/posts/osx-screen-shot-ruler.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This article explains in more detail.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can  &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/page-ruler/jlpkojjdgbllmedoapgfodplfhcbnbpn/related?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install the easy Page Ruler addon  for Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve figured out what dimensions your images should be, you can use any of the below tools to resize your images accordingly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resizing Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIMP – free, Windows &amp;amp; Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irfan View- free for Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preview for Mac – it’s already installed!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers on Macs can &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/sips.1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;check out sips, a command line tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Tools For Resizing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picmonkey.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pixlr.com (also has mobile app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fotor.com (also has mobile app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter which one you use – all you need to do is locate the resize feature. You’ll be able to enter the desired pixel width and the application will make sure the image stays in proportion by adjusting the height automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;image-formats&#34;&gt;Image Formats&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images on the web should be saved in either .jpg, .png, or possibly .gif&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JPEGs&lt;/strong&gt; are best used for photographs and general purpose images where you do not need any transparency. You can compress them easily and get a smaller filesize suitable for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PNGs&lt;/strong&gt; will often generate a larger filesize so should only be used when you have an image that requires transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GIFs&lt;/strong&gt; are less frequently used. They have a limited range of color so can only be used for very simple images, but can produce a small filesize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;compressing-images&#34;&gt;Compressing Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’ve dealt with the physical dimensions of the image, now let’s deal with the ‘weight’ of the image. We want to compress the image to make it as lean and fast-loading as possible. &lt;strong&gt;The goal is to reduce the filesize&lt;/strong&gt;. There isn’t a magic number as to what each image should be, since it depends on how the image will be used. Images being used in a hero banner or slider will be bigger, but if you have a few of them, I’d aim to get each one down to 100KB or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small images that are going to be used for thumbnails, logos etc will be much much smaller. The logo at the top of this blog, for example, is 3.8KB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With compression there may be a slight loss in quality, so you’re looking for a balance between quality and file size. But always remember that the smaller the filesize, the faster the load time will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoshop – make sure to use the &lt;em&gt;Save For Web&lt;/em&gt; option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ImageOptim (Mac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compressor.io – make sure to choose the ‘lossy’ option for the biggest size reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wordpress-plugins&#34;&gt;WordPress Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s preferable to resize and compress your image before you upload it to WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if your site is already live, you will need to deal with the images that are already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the crucial images such as logos, headers and others that load on every page of your site, it would be best to make new versions of the images as described above, then install the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/enable-media-replace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enable Media Replace plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This will allow you to simply replace existing images in your media library with the new, optimized ones, without breaking any links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the other images sitting in your media library, where it would be unrealistic to go through and fix them all individually,there are a few handy plugins that will help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/ewww-image-optimizer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EWWW Image Optimizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plugin can go through your existing media library and compress everything in bulk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build sites for clients or have a site with multiple users where you cannot ensure that everyone is using best practices and uploading nicely optimized images, the below plugins will help mitigate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/imsanity/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Imsanity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can determine the settings so that if someone uploads a gigantic image, it will automatically be reduced to maximum size of your choosing. No more 4000 pixel images clogging up the media library!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/tiny-compress-images/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Compress JPEG &amp;amp; PNG Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once set up, this uses the TinyPNG API to automatically compress images on upload. You can get a free API key for up to 500 images/month which would be plenty for the average blogger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to benchmark the speed of your site, or do before/after comparisons with images after optimizing, &lt;a title=&#34;How To Correctly Measure Your Website’s Page Load Time&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/?p=33279&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;follow this guide on how to properly measure the load time of your site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does SSL Protect My Website?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 17:12:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most economical and secure ways to protect your website on affordable hosting platforms is to deploy a private Secure Socket Layer (SSL) on you’re your website giving the instant ability to roll out protected URLs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysite.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.mysite.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still in doubt as to what an SSL actually does consider this explanation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symantec.com/theme.jsp?themeid=how-ssl-works&#34;&gt;Symantec&lt;/a&gt; on the digital handshake that takes place between a browser and a server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A browser attempts to connect to a website secured with SSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser requests that the web server identify itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends the browser a copy of its SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser checks whether it trusts the SSL certificate. If so, it sends a message to the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends back a digitally signed acknowledgement to start an SSL 7 encrypted session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypted data is shared between the browser and the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your site receives a permanent “security guard” which protects users in an online transaction, and encrypts data during transmission giving you, said Symantec, a “trillion year head start over a hacker.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At current computing speeds, a hacker with the time, tools, and motivation to attack using brute force would require a trillion years to break into a session protected by an SGC-enabled certificate,” said Symantec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To enable strong encryption for the most site visitors, choose an SSL Certificate that enables 128-bit minimum encryption for 99.9 percent of website visitors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are other benefits, too, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials establish identity online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication generates trust in credential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSL certificates on Intispace platforms are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed by Comodo, Geotrust, RapidSSL, Certum, Thawte, Symantec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99.3% compatibility with browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;256-bit encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lock appears in browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not try Outsmart Google’s Algorithm To Achieve Your SEO</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/do-not-try-outsmart-googles-algorithm-to-achieve-your-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 11:54:33 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/do-not-try-outsmart-googles-algorithm-to-achieve-your-seo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;**Instead of trying to cheat the major search engines’ algorithms, come up with compelling content that reaches your audience. The SEO will follow.**&lt;/p&gt; 

Far too often businesses try to crack the SEO “code” in order to arrive at the number one spot on Google. However, with a continually changing algorithm and no guarantee for success, your best bet is to focus on your audience, not the search engine.

Google, along with other popular search engines such as Yahoo and Bing, attempt to reward sites that have compelling content that actually meet their visitors’ needs. The algorithms are designed to display the absolute best result for keywords that are entered into a search bar.

This isn’t to say that there aren’t little tweaks and adjustments that SEOs make in order to boost your search engine rankings. But when it really comes down to it some of the simplest changes to your site can greatly boost your web presence. We take a look at four details you can implement into your site’s plan to fit a search engine’s ever-changing mold:

**It starts with the framework**

The design and development of your site is crucial for achieving a [high SEO ranking][1]. This starts with how you lay out your site and ends with the final development. Building a crawl-friendly website that allows your user to easily navigate the site will drastically improve your site’s rankings.

Start by creating a sitemap and a wireframe. Don’t even consider developing the site until you have a firm design for your site that will allow for a smooth UX (User Experience). [Take a look at these other guidelines][2] you should follow when designing and developing your site.

If a search engine can’t navigate through your site, you will not achieve the rankings that you desire.

**Implement a blog**

There are many reasons to start a [blog for your business][3], and improving SEO is at the top of the list. You don’t have to be a world-renowned author to write intriguing blog posts. All you need is a passion for your subject matter and a desire to share some of your insights with your clients and visitors.

Having a blog that you frequently update (we suggest posting at least once a week) greatly increases the number of pages related to your site. Every post you publish creates another chance for a potential visitor to find your site.

As with all other SEO practices, focus on creating content that will apply to your audience. Write blog posts that your visitors can actually relate to. As you build a strong library of posts, and as you gain followers, you will be able to add more links, and outside blogs will start linking to you, eventually building a large network.

**Social Media**

Similar to having a blog, having your business on various social media platforms builds a network and adds to the number of sources a search engine can display for your business. Try searching for a business you’re familiar with and see how far down their Twitter or Facebook page appears on the SERP (Search Engine Results Page). Most likely it’s near the top.

Social media also gives you [a chance to interact with your clients][4]. Instead of paying thousands for advertising that reaches the wrong demographic, you’re displaying information that leads directly to those who are following you.

In addition to these benefits of social media, a Tweet that goes viral or a Facebook post that gets shared over 1000 times will build more links, eventually helping your rankings.

**Focusing on keywords and content**

We arrive back to what SEO is really about: creating content that your visitors actually want to see. The best way to do this is by including the keywords that your clients will be searching for.

[The role of keywords in SEO has changed][5] over the years, but there’s no arguing that they still affect how a user finds and views your site. If you’re not using the keywords that your audience is typing in, it’s unlikely that they’ll arrive at your site.

Possibly the best route for SEO success is defining your audience and finding the words that they will be searching for. [&lt;section&gt;**Instead of trying to cheat the major search engines’ algorithms, come up with compelling content that reaches your audience. The SEO will follow.**&lt;/p&gt; 

Far too often businesses try to crack the SEO “code” in order to arrive at the number one spot on Google. However, with a continually changing algorithm and no guarantee for success, your best bet is to focus on your audience, not the search engine.

Google, along with other popular search engines such as Yahoo and Bing, attempt to reward sites that have compelling content that actually meet their visitors’ needs. The algorithms are designed to display the absolute best result for keywords that are entered into a search bar.

This isn’t to say that there aren’t little tweaks and adjustments that SEOs make in order to boost your search engine rankings. But when it really comes down to it some of the simplest changes to your site can greatly boost your web presence. We take a look at four details you can implement into your site’s plan to fit a search engine’s ever-changing mold:

**It starts with the framework**

The design and development of your site is crucial for achieving a [high SEO ranking][1]. This starts with how you lay out your site and ends with the final development. Building a crawl-friendly website that allows your user to easily navigate the site will drastically improve your site’s rankings.

Start by creating a sitemap and a wireframe. Don’t even consider developing the site until you have a firm design for your site that will allow for a smooth UX (User Experience). [Take a look at these other guidelines][2] you should follow when designing and developing your site.

If a search engine can’t navigate through your site, you will not achieve the rankings that you desire.

**Implement a blog**

There are many reasons to start a [blog for your business][3], and improving SEO is at the top of the list. You don’t have to be a world-renowned author to write intriguing blog posts. All you need is a passion for your subject matter and a desire to share some of your insights with your clients and visitors.

Having a blog that you frequently update (we suggest posting at least once a week) greatly increases the number of pages related to your site. Every post you publish creates another chance for a potential visitor to find your site.

As with all other SEO practices, focus on creating content that will apply to your audience. Write blog posts that your visitors can actually relate to. As you build a strong library of posts, and as you gain followers, you will be able to add more links, and outside blogs will start linking to you, eventually building a large network.

**Social Media**

Similar to having a blog, having your business on various social media platforms builds a network and adds to the number of sources a search engine can display for your business. Try searching for a business you’re familiar with and see how far down their Twitter or Facebook page appears on the SERP (Search Engine Results Page). Most likely it’s near the top.

Social media also gives you [a chance to interact with your clients][4]. Instead of paying thousands for advertising that reaches the wrong demographic, you’re displaying information that leads directly to those who are following you.

In addition to these benefits of social media, a Tweet that goes viral or a Facebook post that gets shared over 1000 times will build more links, eventually helping your rankings.

**Focusing on keywords and content**

We arrive back to what SEO is really about: creating content that your visitors actually want to see. The best way to do this is by including the keywords that your clients will be searching for.

[The role of keywords in SEO has changed][5] over the years, but there’s no arguing that they still affect how a user finds and views your site. If you’re not using the keywords that your audience is typing in, it’s unlikely that they’ll arrive at your site.

Possibly the best route for SEO success is defining your audience and finding the words that they will be searching for.][6] is a great resource for helping you find the keywords that you should include in your content. Once you know what your customers are actually searching for, you can refine your content to meet those needs.

Rather than spending time trying to crack the so-called “Google code”, try focusing on creating a site that contains compelling and linkable content. Search engines strive to determine which site will fit your customers’ needs. Create a content plan that fulfills these needs, eventually leading your site to the top of the SERP. Keep checking the [intispace blog][7] for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.

Also, send us a tweet [@intispace][8] with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!

&amp;nbsp;

This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here [www.intispace.com][9]&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO 1001</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/04/seo-1001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 07:49:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/04/seo-1001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;header&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;posted-by&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Where do you start with S.E.O?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/header&gt; &lt;section&gt;Yes, SEO. You’d be surprised how many people put it on their resume. After all, it’s just adding a heap of keywords into a webpage or blog post isn’t it? In a word. No. It’s not. Search Engine Optimization refers to a cosmos worth of rules and principles. What’s more, that cosmos is changing all the time.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;SEO guru Rand Fishkin, who founded The MOZ, defines the complexity of his field as follows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“SEO is any input that search engines use to rank pages. Anything that people or technology does to influence those elements is what the practice of SEO is all about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opens up all kinds of Pandora boxes. However, everyone has to start somewhere. Getting good at SEO begins with baby steps. Here are a few footsteps to follow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential S.E.O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tips are pretty much best-practice. These alone won’t get you the number one spot in the search engine rankings, but they will lay the foundations for the future…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Submission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step towards getting your website noticed by the search engines is to tell them about it. All the big search engines make it easy for you to submit your site to them. It takes less than 30 seconds for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/submit-url?pli=1&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com/toolbox/submit-site-url&#34;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawl Friendly Web Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web crawler is a computer program that search engines use to gather the data they need to rank a website in their listings. To make your website crawler-friendly you can do things like break up your web pages into chunks of copy with easily identifiable headlines for each section. It’s also helpful to upload a sitemap in XML format to your website. This will help crawlers navigate your site, especially if it’s a complex one. If you have pages on your website that you think might be misleading or irrelevant to a customer’s search aims, you can place a text file called robots.txt in the root of the website hierarchy. This will tell crawlers to disregard these pages. You can also use certain Google Webmaster tools to help identify crawl errors that could damage a site’s SEO ranking. Finally, try to avoid hiding important text in graphics, because crawlers can’t read this text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-2898 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/keywords-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;keywords&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research should help you get the right sort of visitors to your site. Keywords are the words that customers type into the search bar when they are looking for a service or product. Spending time researching these keywords can help your website appear in the search listings in relation to these keywords. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/what-google-exact-match-adword-changes-mean-for-your-business/&#34;&gt;Google Adwords&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool for figuring out the value of keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a good idea to do some research into the keywords your competition seem to be using – what keywords do they seem to be trying to use and what keywords do they rank well for? Plenty of tools exist to do this for you – just pop in the competitor’s URL and press go – all their secrets will be revealed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.seobook.com/general/keyword-density/%20&#34;&gt;SEO book&lt;/a&gt; is popular tool for doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research isn’t just something you need to do once. It’s a practice you need to keep updating constantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years Google has done everything in its power to stop people from cheating at SEO. Therefore, they’ve made it important for websites to feature quality relevant content. More specifically, content that is is expert and informative. Setting up a blog and using it to comment on relevant issues or to offer helpful advice can contribute to your content ticking the right boxes with the search engines. The mantra must alway be ‘make it useful for your visitors and do not focus on search engines and keywords’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Level SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got the basics sorted, you can try to make your website more competitive by following these tips…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engaging Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think you’ve written a masterpiece on your blog, but it doesn’t count for much if it’s not getting engagement. By this we mean social media shares and the encouragement of other websites and blogs to link to your work. Content is more likely to be shared if it solves a problem, raises an emotion, supports a cause, or offers an incentive for sharing. You can use free tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics/&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; to work out which pieces of your content are proving most popular with your visitors. In addition, you can use sites like Google Trends and Quora to get a better insight about what people are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again check out your competition to find out who is doing content really well in your market. Once you have found them check out what they are writing about and see what is getting the best shares and reader engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright wp-image-2899 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/SEO-links-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SEO links&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organic Link Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links are still a huge factor in website rankings. Anything that promotes link growth helps SEO. However, don’t be tempted to cheat at this, because Google has ways of blacklisting sites who do things like pay for links in shady places. You can increase the number of links to your site by forming relationships with bloggers and writing guests posts for them. As with any blogging activity, make sure what you write is bang on topic and useful for the audience. Pushing out the same lightweight piece and content with deep links and keywords will actually do you harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid any kind of automated or mass link building practices like blog comment spam, profile links, social bookmarking and article marketing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/guest-blogging/&#34;&gt;spam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting your content on social media can work wonders for your SEO. For example, studies have shown that content that is tweeted about a lot will be indexed by Google up to 50 percent faster than content that has not been put on social media. Social media is also a great place to get people talking about your brand,[&lt;header&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;posted-by&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Where do you start with S.E.O?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/header&gt; &lt;section&gt;Yes, SEO. You’d be surprised how many people put it on their resume. After all, it’s just adding a heap of keywords into a webpage or blog post isn’t it? In a word. No. It’s not. Search Engine Optimization refers to a cosmos worth of rules and principles. What’s more, that cosmos is changing all the time.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;SEO guru Rand Fishkin, who founded The MOZ, defines the complexity of his field as follows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“SEO is any input that search engines use to rank pages. Anything that people or technology does to influence those elements is what the practice of SEO is all about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opens up all kinds of Pandora boxes. However, everyone has to start somewhere. Getting good at SEO begins with baby steps. Here are a few footsteps to follow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential S.E.O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tips are pretty much best-practice. These alone won’t get you the number one spot in the search engine rankings, but they will lay the foundations for the future…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Submission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step towards getting your website noticed by the search engines is to tell them about it. All the big search engines make it easy for you to submit your site to them. It takes less than 30 seconds for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/submit-url?pli=1&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com/toolbox/submit-site-url&#34;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawl Friendly Web Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web crawler is a computer program that search engines use to gather the data they need to rank a website in their listings. To make your website crawler-friendly you can do things like break up your web pages into chunks of copy with easily identifiable headlines for each section. It’s also helpful to upload a sitemap in XML format to your website. This will help crawlers navigate your site, especially if it’s a complex one. If you have pages on your website that you think might be misleading or irrelevant to a customer’s search aims, you can place a text file called robots.txt in the root of the website hierarchy. This will tell crawlers to disregard these pages. You can also use certain Google Webmaster tools to help identify crawl errors that could damage a site’s SEO ranking. Finally, try to avoid hiding important text in graphics, because crawlers can’t read this text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-2898 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/keywords-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;keywords&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research should help you get the right sort of visitors to your site. Keywords are the words that customers type into the search bar when they are looking for a service or product. Spending time researching these keywords can help your website appear in the search listings in relation to these keywords. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/what-google-exact-match-adword-changes-mean-for-your-business/&#34;&gt;Google Adwords&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool for figuring out the value of keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a good idea to do some research into the keywords your competition seem to be using – what keywords do they seem to be trying to use and what keywords do they rank well for? Plenty of tools exist to do this for you – just pop in the competitor’s URL and press go – all their secrets will be revealed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.seobook.com/general/keyword-density/%20&#34;&gt;SEO book&lt;/a&gt; is popular tool for doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research isn’t just something you need to do once. It’s a practice you need to keep updating constantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years Google has done everything in its power to stop people from cheating at SEO. Therefore, they’ve made it important for websites to feature quality relevant content. More specifically, content that is is expert and informative. Setting up a blog and using it to comment on relevant issues or to offer helpful advice can contribute to your content ticking the right boxes with the search engines. The mantra must alway be ‘make it useful for your visitors and do not focus on search engines and keywords’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Level SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got the basics sorted, you can try to make your website more competitive by following these tips…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engaging Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think you’ve written a masterpiece on your blog, but it doesn’t count for much if it’s not getting engagement. By this we mean social media shares and the encouragement of other websites and blogs to link to your work. Content is more likely to be shared if it solves a problem, raises an emotion, supports a cause, or offers an incentive for sharing. You can use free tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics/&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; to work out which pieces of your content are proving most popular with your visitors. In addition, you can use sites like Google Trends and Quora to get a better insight about what people are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again check out your competition to find out who is doing content really well in your market. Once you have found them check out what they are writing about and see what is getting the best shares and reader engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright wp-image-2899 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/SEO-links-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SEO links&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organic Link Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links are still a huge factor in website rankings. Anything that promotes link growth helps SEO. However, don’t be tempted to cheat at this, because Google has ways of blacklisting sites who do things like pay for links in shady places. You can increase the number of links to your site by forming relationships with bloggers and writing guests posts for them. As with any blogging activity, make sure what you write is bang on topic and useful for the audience. Pushing out the same lightweight piece and content with deep links and keywords will actually do you harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid any kind of automated or mass link building practices like blog comment spam, profile links, social bookmarking and article marketing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/guest-blogging/&#34;&gt;spam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting your content on social media can work wonders for your SEO. For example, studies have shown that content that is tweeted about a lot will be indexed by Google up to 50 percent faster than content that has not been put on social media. Social media is also a great place to get people talking about your brand,]&lt;a href=&#34;http://adage.com/article/media/google-s-schmidt-internet-cesspool-brands/131569/&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt; have said over and over again that branding is very important for ranking. If you build your brand visibility you’ll build your ranking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building your SEO requires marathon mentality rather than the race approach. It takes considerable time to see results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you could always consider pay per click and display advertising to garner yourself some attention online. Display advertising is simply online advertising and it refers to things like banner ads and pay per click adverts. You need a bit of a budget to invest in this sort of advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
