<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Web Server on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/categories/web-server/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 09:22:48 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAKE SURE YOUR MOVERS ARE PROFESSIONALS</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/make-sure-your-movers-are-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 09:22:48 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/make-sure-your-movers-are-professionals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever had to move, you know how difficult it can be. It doesn’t matter if you’re moving your website to a new host or your family to a new house. Even if your current location causes you a lot of stress, the pain of moving somewhere new can make it seem worthwhile to stay in a place you’re not happy. Moving doesn’t have to be a massive difficulty for you, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My old friend, Christian Dubois moved his houses earlier this week. To help alleviate the pain, he hired professionals. He did research on moving companies, discovering that many hire part-time or seasonal employees. That terrified him. Some people may say stuff is just stuff, but it’s my stuff and much of it is very important to me. He was hiring professionals to reduce his stress, not simply replace it with the worry that inexperienced movers might break things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving hosting sucks, make sure your movers are professionals. When people move from an old host to Intispace, we know the process can be stressful. No one wants to escape a bad host only to find their website doesn’t work properly on the new one. That’s why we train our expert staff to move people safely and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s your home, your business, or your website, moving sucks. Working with trusted professionals like Intispace lets you relax while they take care of all the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does SSL Protect My Website?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 17:12:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most economical and secure ways to protect your website on affordable hosting platforms is to deploy a private Secure Socket Layer (SSL) on you’re your website giving the instant ability to roll out protected URLs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysite.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.mysite.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still in doubt as to what an SSL actually does consider this explanation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symantec.com/theme.jsp?themeid=how-ssl-works&#34;&gt;Symantec&lt;/a&gt; on the digital handshake that takes place between a browser and a server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A browser attempts to connect to a website secured with SSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser requests that the web server identify itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends the browser a copy of its SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser checks whether it trusts the SSL certificate. If so, it sends a message to the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends back a digitally signed acknowledgement to start an SSL 7 encrypted session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypted data is shared between the browser and the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your site receives a permanent “security guard” which protects users in an online transaction, and encrypts data during transmission giving you, said Symantec, a “trillion year head start over a hacker.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At current computing speeds, a hacker with the time, tools, and motivation to attack using brute force would require a trillion years to break into a session protected by an SGC-enabled certificate,” said Symantec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To enable strong encryption for the most site visitors, choose an SSL Certificate that enables 128-bit minimum encryption for 99.9 percent of website visitors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are other benefits, too, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials establish identity online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication generates trust in credential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSL certificates on Intispace platforms are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed by Comodo, Geotrust, RapidSSL, Certum, Thawte, Symantec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99.3% compatibility with browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;256-bit encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lock appears in browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
