<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Dns Server on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/categories/dns-server/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 11 May 2015 10:18:07 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned from The Domain Name Survey</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-we-learned-from-the-domain-name-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 10:18:07 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-we-learned-from-the-domain-name-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Domain Name Association conducted a global survey to understand internet users’ thoughts and opinions regarding domain names. Check out the results below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the period of October – November 2014, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.researchnow.com/en-US.aspx&#34;&gt;Research Now&lt;/a&gt; conducted a survey for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedna.org/&#34;&gt;Domain Name Association.&lt;/a&gt; The Domain Name Association, or DNA, is a new non-profit global business association that represents the interests of the domain name industry. The DNA’s primary intent of the survey was to see what people around the world think of &lt;a href=&#34;http://newgtlds.icann.org/&#34;&gt;ICANN’s gTLD program. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedna.org/pr_20150204.php&#34;&gt;DNA&lt;/a&gt;, the survey was designed “to measure global attitudes about awareness, acceptance, preference and knowledge related to domain names.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey involved 5,000 internet users across 10 countries. It consisted of 31 questions and took about 12-16 minutes for respondents to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the survey, DNA tested top-level generic names (e.g. .com, .org); country codes (e.g. .us, .us), along with new generic top-level names (e.g. .press, .club).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the complete results from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://thedna.org/documents/Global_Domain_Name_Preferences_Survey-Domain_Name_Association-Feb2015.pdf&#34;&gt;Domain Name Association&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, read on for the general conclusions that we made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, people around the world are open to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/03/a-glance-of-top-level-domains-and-subdomains/&#34;&gt;new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although .com is still the preferred TLD in the US and UK, other gTLDs received a considerable amount of attention. This was also especially true in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in Australia, 33.9% of respondents said that they’d go to shoes.melbourne to purchase shoes online. This is compared to only 7.2% that would go to shoes.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This varies greatly in the US where only 14% prefer a new TLD over .com. The UK was close, with only 20% saying they’d rather have a new TLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that the relevance of the domain name extension is extremely important to internet users. For example, when respondents were asked: “Where would you go to pay bills online?”, 35% of the US respondents said onlinepayments.secure. The other options, other than onlinepayments.com, received very low responses at around 1%. This shows that .secure adds a sense of security and relevancy to what the user is doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain names are still relevant when browsing the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although search engines have changed the way we locate websites, 85% of respondents said that they enter the entire domain name in the address bar at least some of the time. Out of those surveyed, 94% said that they at least sometimes check the domain name before clicking on a search result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of internet users are not aware of the new gTLD program. In fact, 75% of respondents were either unaware or unsure of the expansion of domain names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the majority agreed that expansion is necessary. When asked if there should be more domain name and domain-name extension options, nearly 60% replied yes. In developing countries, the request for more domain name options was even higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked why new extensions would be welcome, over 50% replied that new web addresses in meaningful combinations will be easier to remember. In a similarly phrased question, over 50% said new domain name extensions will make it easier to obtain short memorable names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we learned from the survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey results confirm that expanding domain name options is a positive action for the internet’s growth. This will be absolutely necessary as more and more websites are created. Luckily the majority of internet users seem willing to adapt to the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, many of those interviewed actually preferred ccTLDs and gTLDs over a generic domain such as .com (with the exception of the US and the UK who still prefer .com for most instances).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the results Kurt Pritz, Executive Director of the DNA, said, “These are important findings for the Domain-Name industry, indicating a bright future for all domain-name extensions. When Internet users generally become aware of the new domain options, we expect widespread acceptance and even eagerness to adopt them”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the domain name reselling business the survey produces great news. The number of domain names, whether generic or new, will only increase as time goes on. Be sure to look for which new domain names are the most successful in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;Intispace.com&lt;/a&gt; specializes in scalable wordpress hosting. Use these survey results to see which domain names you’re most interested in building website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glance Guide to DNS</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/a-glance-guide-to-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 10:04:36 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/a-glance-guide-to-dns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a quick behind-the-scenes tour of how DNS works to connect you to your desired webpage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is no longer just a nice-to-have feature. It has become a significant part of our lives, with most people connecting to the internet every single day. Although millions of people are online at any given time, many don’t understand what is going on behind the scenes. When you enter something in the address bar, how does the browser know exactly where to go? DNS is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS stands for Domain Name System. Everything on the internet would crash if it weren’t for DNS’s intricate processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll begin by explaining what a domain is. The concept of domain names is fairly easy to grasp. Basically, a domain name is a unique name that identifies a website. Behind every domain name is an IP address that is made up of many different numbers. IP addresses, or Internet Protocol addresses, are how computers and servers communicate with each other. Once an IP address is located, a web browser can open the desired web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This long list of numbers is very difficult to remember, hence why we have a domain name to make it easier. For example, the IP address of the domain google.com is 173.194.40.167. You could copy and paste this IP address in your browser and you would be directed to google.com. However, this would be an extremely tedious and difficult task to remember this 11 number code every time you want to access google.com. Domain names have simplified this task for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key point with domains is that the domain name is google.com, not just google. If you don’t type the .com, you are not going to arrive at google.com. The TLD, or Top Level Domain, is the .com (or .org, .uk, .net, etc.) part of a domain name. Without this, the server will not know where to look and the website will not be accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving onto DNS. Simply put, DNS is a worldwide system that translates these domain names (e.g. google.com) into IP addresses. Once your computer has the IP address, it can access the web page and you can begin to access content. At the end of every domain, there is a “dot” that we never see. Google.com is actually google.com.. This “dot” at the end of the domain tells your operating system exactly where to look for the Root name servers. Although we don’t have to type in this extra “dot”, it is necessary behind the scenes in order to find the right IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are going to run through how your computer can find the appropriate IP address and load a web page. We’ll break down the process in six “simple” steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s say you want to find &lt;a href=&#34;http://vps.net/&#34;&gt;vps.net&lt;/a&gt;. You type in the domain name and wait.  As you do this, your computer begins searching for the right IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the IP address is not saved in temporary storage, or cache, it looks to your router. Your router will do the same: it will search in its cache, and if it isn’t there it will look elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your router will look to its configured DNS server(s). If the IP address is not cached there, it will look to the Root name servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Root name server will recognize that your web page is a .com TLD, and will direct the DNS server to the .com servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The .com server can then direct the DNS server to the correct DNS server to retrieve records (the site’s web hosting provider). The records are then transmitted back to the computer and the browser can access the IP address and convert the coded files into a fully usable web page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The site’s DNS records should now be stored in your computer’s cache for easy access. How long it will be stored will depend on the TTL, or Time to Live. You can change your TTL settings depending on your preferences. Generally, they are set for 24 hours. Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchnetworking.techtarget.com/definition/time-to-live&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more details about TTL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These “simple” steps all take place faster than I can hit the spacebar on my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS is commonly referred to as the “phonebook” of the internet. All domains are registered in this phonebook, but by different companies. Web hosting can be seen as the link between your site and your future visitors. &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;Most web hosting companies will register your domain name and provide you with all the DNS information you need&lt;/a&gt;. That way, when your client tries to access your site, they go through the DNS process and are directed to your web hosting provider, who will have your site saved on their servers. From there, your client can access the site from the web hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process may seem daunting and confusing (and yes, it is a bit complicated), but it is a fascinating process that goes on all day, every day. In fact, I used DNS multiple times while writing this post without even thinking about it. Every time I clicked in my address bar to look up a word or to find a link, DNS was hard at work to direct me to the correct IP address. DNS provides us with a fast online experience that doesn’t require much work on our part. Let’s give it up for DNS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
