<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Few Tips For Your New Website on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/tags/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:00:06 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Tips For Your New Website</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:00:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you launch your brand new website, make sure you take these quick tips into account.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1737&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few tips for your new website, creating a new website can be a lot of work. Between coming up with a design, building the site (or hiring a developer) and marketing the new idea, you’re putting in several hours to ensure that your site will draw in new visitors while keeping the current ones engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you hit these targets  to increase customer engagement with your new website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile-friendly design.&lt;/strong&gt; 64% of Americans now have a smartphone, and most of them are using them to access the internet on a daily basis. Make sure your site is easily accessible and navigable from a mobile device. Not only is it important to create a smooth browsing experience for mobile users, Google now actually penalizes sites that aren’t deemed “mobile friendly”. Make sure mobile-friendly design is at the top of your list. We suggest looking at responsive web design for best results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to action.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t simply want your visitors going to your site, admiring the good design, and leaving. You want them to take action. Make sure you include a strong Call To Action (CTA) on your homepage. Make your CTA obvious and simple to follow. Your visitors should find it easy to sign up for your newsletter, make a purchase or give you feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved usability.&lt;/strong&gt; Your site should be visually appealing, but that counts for nothing if your visitors can’t find their way around your site. Usability is key when trying to keep your visitors on your site. To improve usability, make sure you consider your audience when designing your site. Will they know where to click next? Are you answering their questions? Will they be frustrated with anything on the site? Your visitors will leave right away if they’re confused about your site’s layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less is more.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t go overboard with excessive design. Think about usability first, and then make your site appealing to the eye. By using the right typography for your brand, tying in a consistent color scheme and including images that send the right message, you’re on your way to an effective, user-friendly design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informative ‘About Us’ page.&lt;/strong&gt; Let your visitors know exactly who you are and what kind of values your business has. An ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/what-does-your-about-us-page-really-say/&#34;&gt;About Us’ page should be informative and honest&lt;/a&gt;; people love seeing what really lies at the core of a company. If you’re a well-established business, display some of your accomplishments throughout the years. If you’re an up-and-coming startup, outline some of your goals for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compelling copy.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes back to finding your audience and talking directly to them. Now that someone has arrived at your site, pitch them your message! Copy should sound convincing, but you never want to come off as too salesy or intrusive. Be conversational and provide the answers that they’re searching for (that’s why most people are online – to get answers!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When in doubt, A/B test!&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes there’s no way of knowing which design will perform best. When launching your site, try a few different designs and see which one produces optimal results. This way, there is no doubting which design will work better for your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed up your site.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s almost nothing that will drive away your visitors more quickly than &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/&#34;&gt;slow loading times&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, 40% of people say they will leave a page if it takes longer than 3 seconds to load. Check out this blog post to see how you can easily speed up your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
