<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Domain Names on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/categories/domain-names/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 10:14:18 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP DAVID BOWIE</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2016/01/rip-david-bowie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 10:14:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2016/01/rip-david-bowie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And the internet now carries the flag of being subversive and possibly rebellious, and chaotic and nihilistic….I think the potential of what the Internet is going to do to society both good and bad is unimaginable. I think we’re on the cusp of something exhilarating and terrifying.”&lt;/em&gt; – David Bowie, 2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIP DAVID BOWIE, To say that David Bowie was a pioneer was an understatement.  Not only did he redefine music and culture in a way never seen before or since — he even defined how technology was being used to spread culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know the gender-bending costumes and far out stories he told in his songs, but did you know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jan/11/david-bowie-bowienet-isp-internet&#34;&gt;David Bowie was an internet mogul too&lt;/a&gt;?  He was the first major artist to do an online-only distribution of a song back in 1996. Before sending tweets or liking a YouTube video, you could join BowieNet, which would allow you to chat with the artist, share links, and even launch your own web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Bowie understood that the internet was not just bits and bytes, but a communication channel that connected people in ways never seen in history. He saw how disruptive it was to cultures around the world. Only years later would we all see Bowie’s vision unfold to shape not only music, but all future human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIP DAVID BOWIE, Thank you for your vision and inspiration to us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/FACTmagazine/videos/10153819928364687/&#34;&gt;interview of David Bowie&lt;/a&gt; discussing the power of the internet back in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things to do before buying a domain</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/12/things-buying-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 07:09:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/12/things-buying-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;postcontents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Domains are relatively easy to purchase: You just head over to &lt;a href=&#34;http://intispace.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;your favorite registrar&lt;/a&gt;, type in the domain you’re interested in, and as long as it’s available, it can be yours with a few clicks of a button. But the real work comes &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; you make your purchase..
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    If you want to register a great domain name that will set you up for success in the long run, perform these things to do before buying a domain before hitting the “&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;&#34;&gt;Purchase&lt;/span&gt;” button.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Give yourself time to really think about your domain name before committing to one
  &lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Things to do before buying a domain. Your first idea for a domain name may not be your best one. Give yourself time to think over possibilities and come up with several options to choose from. After all, a great domain name is the foundation of a good website. It should be memorable, easy to type, and effectively share your brand. Also, think beyond traditional domain endings and consider using a New Domain. Not only does it offer you the chance to create a uniquely branded URL, but it also has a lot more availability than traditional domain names.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Determine how you’ll be using your domain
  &lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Things to do before buying a domain. You have several options for how to use your domain once it’s registered. The most obvious way to use it is as the primary URL for a new website—but that’s not your only option. You can maximize your online presence by pointing your domain to a variety of other places. Highlight a specific section of your website through a customized domain (for example, showcase your philanthropy efforts with a yoursite.gives domain), or make it easy for new followers to find you on social media with a yoursite.social domain name.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h2&gt;
    Make sure you’re not infringing on someone else’s trademark
  &lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Things to do before buying a domain. There’s always a possibility that the brilliant, perfect, one-of-a-kind domain name you’ve come up with isn’t as unique as you thought. If it turns out that your domain is the same or very similar to trademarked content, you could be in big trouble down the road. It’s worth the extra effort to do your research ahead of time to make sure you aren’t infringing upon someone else’s intellectual property. A quick Google search is a good place to start, but you can also use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uspto.gov/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;U.S. Patent and Trademark Office website&lt;/a&gt; to do more in-depth research. Nolo.com also offers a comprehensive guide for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nolo.com/legal-encyclopedia/avoid-trademark-infringement-domain-name-29032.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;understanding if your domain name infringes on a trademark&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  
  &lt;h2&gt;
    See if social handles of the same (or a similar) name are available
  &lt;/h2&gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    Social media is now an essential part of curating an online presence. You want it to be as easy as possible for your website visitors to find and follow you on other social networks. Having a consistent handle across your website and social media accounts streamlines your online presence and is a great way to brand yourself. With the right tools, it doesn’t take a lot of work to determine if a name is available across the board. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.name.com/blog/business/social-media-2/2015/09/rembrandt-social-media-branding-made-easy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download the Chrome extension Rembrandt&lt;/a&gt; and whenever you search for a domain name on intispace.com, you’ll automatically see if the same handles are available on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and Pinterest.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Tips For Your New Website</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:00:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you launch your brand new website, make sure you take these quick tips into account.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1737&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few tips for your new website, creating a new website can be a lot of work. Between coming up with a design, building the site (or hiring a developer) and marketing the new idea, you’re putting in several hours to ensure that your site will draw in new visitors while keeping the current ones engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you hit these targets  to increase customer engagement with your new website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile-friendly design.&lt;/strong&gt; 64% of Americans now have a smartphone, and most of them are using them to access the internet on a daily basis. Make sure your site is easily accessible and navigable from a mobile device. Not only is it important to create a smooth browsing experience for mobile users, Google now actually penalizes sites that aren’t deemed “mobile friendly”. Make sure mobile-friendly design is at the top of your list. We suggest looking at responsive web design for best results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to action.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t simply want your visitors going to your site, admiring the good design, and leaving. You want them to take action. Make sure you include a strong Call To Action (CTA) on your homepage. Make your CTA obvious and simple to follow. Your visitors should find it easy to sign up for your newsletter, make a purchase or give you feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved usability.&lt;/strong&gt; Your site should be visually appealing, but that counts for nothing if your visitors can’t find their way around your site. Usability is key when trying to keep your visitors on your site. To improve usability, make sure you consider your audience when designing your site. Will they know where to click next? Are you answering their questions? Will they be frustrated with anything on the site? Your visitors will leave right away if they’re confused about your site’s layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less is more.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t go overboard with excessive design. Think about usability first, and then make your site appealing to the eye. By using the right typography for your brand, tying in a consistent color scheme and including images that send the right message, you’re on your way to an effective, user-friendly design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informative ‘About Us’ page.&lt;/strong&gt; Let your visitors know exactly who you are and what kind of values your business has. An ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/what-does-your-about-us-page-really-say/&#34;&gt;About Us’ page should be informative and honest&lt;/a&gt;; people love seeing what really lies at the core of a company. If you’re a well-established business, display some of your accomplishments throughout the years. If you’re an up-and-coming startup, outline some of your goals for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compelling copy.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes back to finding your audience and talking directly to them. Now that someone has arrived at your site, pitch them your message! Copy should sound convincing, but you never want to come off as too salesy or intrusive. Be conversational and provide the answers that they’re searching for (that’s why most people are online – to get answers!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When in doubt, A/B test!&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes there’s no way of knowing which design will perform best. When launching your site, try a few different designs and see which one produces optimal results. This way, there is no doubting which design will work better for your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed up your site.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s almost nothing that will drive away your visitors more quickly than &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/&#34;&gt;slow loading times&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, 40% of people say they will leave a page if it takes longer than 3 seconds to load. Check out this blog post to see how you can easily speed up your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Your Marketing Potential</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/maximize-your-marketing-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2015 12:15:42 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/maximize-your-marketing-potential/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is it worth it for a marketer to become technical, creative and analytical? Read why dedicating time to expanding your skillset will only improve your overall success.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1625&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marketing is a broad field. It is not just about search engine optimization, it isn’t just expanding reach on social media and it definitely isn’t just advertising. Marketing pulls several different components together to form a profitable business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maximize Your Marketing Potential! One of the most important aspects of a well-rounded marketer that is commonly overlooked is having the necessary technical skills. A marketer might ask: why should I learn how to code if I can hire a developer? Or why should I spend time developing my writing skills if I can hire a copywriter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several reasons why it pays to expand your skillset, the first being that you may not be in a position to be hiring other people to work for you. In fact, you may very well be the one &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; hired. When it comes to this, having a wide range of skills will set you apart from the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 7 skills that every marketer (or hopeful entrepreneur) should aim to develop:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web technology and development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)&lt;/strong&gt; – Having a strong grasp on these basic coding languages will benefit you greatly and help you create a strong web presence. Even if you go the route of using a Content Management Software (CMS), you’ll still need to understand how HTML and CSS work. Your website, or the sites you help clients create, will never be up to par if you don’t have a confident base in web development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web design/UX design&lt;/strong&gt; – Although similar to web development, web design and UX design focus on how your audience will interact with a website or web app. Knowing what kind of typography works best or the ideal location of a CTA (Call To Action) can drastically improve how a user browses a webpage. Start by learning how to make sitemaps and wireframes and then deepen your design skills from there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn new software&lt;/strong&gt; – This may depend on the type of work you’ll be doing, but we suggest starting with the Adobe Creative Cloud (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator). Everything from hopeful startups to Fortune 500 companies use programs like Photoshop. In addition to this, become an expert with Excel; this dramatically helps with the following tip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics&lt;/strong&gt; – Evaluating results and testing what is and isn’t working is crucial for a marketer. If something isn’t working you’re more likely to know about it if you have the data as evidence. From this data you can figure out what changes are needed to improve it. And of course if something is working well, the proof is in the data. I had a marketing professor that always said, “In God we trust. All others bring data”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO&lt;/strong&gt; – Search Engine Optimization is a key role for all marketers. In today’s digital age your targeted audience must be able to find you online. How much will your revenue increase if a potential customer finds your site at the top of their Google search? Yeah, SEO is &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copywriting&lt;/strong&gt; – We can all agree that not everyone writes well. However, writing is a skill that can be developed and as with any other kind of skill, practice makes perfect. Don’t be afraid to express your creativity in the copy that you write. This is one of the major opportunities you have to reach out and connect with your audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Databases/SQL&lt;/strong&gt; – Understanding databases can help you pull the data you need to analyze and put it to use. Being able to at least process SQL will give you the ability to look through a database. When you feel more comfortable with it you can even create your own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social media&lt;/strong&gt; – Ten years ago, no one would have taken a marketer who focused only on social media seriously. Now, it’s essential for all marketers to understand how to build a strong social presence. Effectively using Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and Google+ can boost your business from an unknown startup to the next Pebble smartwatch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web hosting&lt;/strong&gt; – As a marketer you may be responsible for getting a site live and making sure it functions properly. You might not be involved with profound server-side protocols, but you should at least understand the basics of hosting, including FTP (File Transfer Protocol) and SSL (Secure Sockets Layer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branding&lt;/strong&gt; – Let’s not forget one of the staple attributes of a good marketer: the ability to brand a product or service. This seems simple to some, but large corporations pay top marketers hundreds of thousands of dollars to build their brand. What makes companies like Apple or Nike or North Face so elite? It boils down to the image that they’ve created for themselves through outstanding marketing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You of course can’t learn all of these skills in only a couple of weeks. It may take years to finally grasp new and foreign concepts such as SEO and JavaScript. However, dedicating the time to learn will only make you a better marketer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To market your business online you need to start by registering a domain name and host a site. See how &lt;a href=&#34;http://intispace.com&#34;&gt;Intispace Netmedia&lt;/a&gt; can help you start your online business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep checking the intispace blog for more upcoming tips on starting your own business. Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here www.intispace.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Measure Your Website’s Page Load Time</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:04 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When assessing the effectiveness of CDN, W3 Total Cache or any other WordPress caching plugin, it’s important that you are able to correctly measure the page loading time of your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several tools available for How To Measure Your Website’s Page Load Time. Our favorite, and the one we think is most accurate, is Pingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-pingdom&#34;&gt;How To Use Pingdom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert info&#34;&gt;
  Visit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.pingdom.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://tools.pingdom.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click Settings and choose the location closest to your web server, not your own physical location. Paste in your website URL and click Test Now.&lt;span id=&#34;more-283&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pingdom will summarize your web page performance at the top with 4 metrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-286  lazyautosizes lazyloaded&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/Website-speed-test-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pindgom website speed test&#34; width=&#34;639&#34; height=&#34;553&#34; data-lazy-src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/Website-speed-test-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these metrics, the most important is load time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grade is a general guideline of how well your site is optimized, but it’s not important to get a perfect score there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed at which your site loads is really the only number that matters. When Google is visiting your site, it does not care or know about the performance grade, only the loading time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-an-accurate-average&#34;&gt;Getting An Accurate Average&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should run the test several times to get an average loading time since it will not be identical every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have just added caching to your site, or have changed any options in your caching plugin, the first time a visitor (including a Pingdom bot) hits your page (unless it’s been preloaded), they will get a non-cached version of the page. That visit causes the cache to be generated, so the next visitor will get the faster, cached version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you run the speed test, the first result could possibly be on a non-cached version of your page which is why it’s important to run the test a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intispace + Cloudflare will preload the homepage of your site and the pages linked from it when you either manually click the Preload button, when the cache has expired or when you create or update a post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, when you create/update content the cache is deleted and preloaded a few seconds later for associated content such as category and tag archive pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you simply use the Clear Cache feature or just save the settings, the preload won’t get triggered. So either trigger it manually, or just visit your website to generate the cache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people only test the homepage of their site which typically has a lot more content on it than a regular page or post. So consider testing various types of content on your site to get a more well-rounded view of how fast your site is as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On many websites, visitors finding the site from a search engine will enter your site on a blog post or individual page, not necessarily the homepage, so the performance of all pages needs to be fast. You’ll probably find that those internal posts/pages load faster than your homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;benchmarking&#34;&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To really see how much improvement you’re getting from your caching plugin you need to benchmark your site without any caching plugins first by running the above tests and taking an average page load time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then add your caching plugin with its most basic configuration and run the tests a few more times to get a comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time you activate a new option in the plugin you need to see if it has an impact – for better or worse, so you need to test each change that you make, in the above manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people turn on W3 Total Cache for example and enable ALL the additional options but find some slowness. This could be because additional options such as minification and others have the potential to conflict with themes, plugins and server configurations and should be used cautiously. They are not always necessary. Just turning on the plugin will give you the most significant speed boost. The additional options are just that – optional. They are not always necessary and should always be tested to see if they are giving you additional improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing after every change lets you isolate a particular feature that may be causing an issue. This is true of W# Total Cache or any of the other caching plugins you may use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, make sure you don’t have multiple caching plugins running at once. For example, even if WP Super Cache is installed but not activated, it can still interfere so it needs to be fully deleted before testing a different plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-waterfall-chart&#34;&gt;The Waterfall Chart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waterfall shows you the loading time of each component of your page – all the various image files, CSS, Javascript files etc that are loaded each time someone visits your page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using a caching plugin such as W3 Total Cache you should be getting a fast loading time, but the waterfall chart can help you identify any bottlenecks or problematic files. Sometimes it only takes a couple of large images or external scripts to drag down the loading time of your page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the dropdown at the top of the waterfall and choose “Sort By Load Time”. This will show you the longest loading files at the top, making problem files easy to spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External scripts such as those from third party ad servers etc are probably your biggest enemy here. Since those scripts are not coming from your server there is no caching you can do on them – you are at the mercy of their server. You can see that in this example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-285 aligncenter  lazyautosizes lazyloaded&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/sort-by-load-time.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pingdom - Sort By Load Time&#34; width=&#34;639&#34; height=&#34;114&#34; data-lazy-src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/sort-by-load-time.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash Your Inner Ninja!</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/unleash-your-inner-ninja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:35:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/unleash-your-inner-ninja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been posting sporadically about various new domain extensions over the last year and we currently offer a very large (and growing) selection. While I’d love to say that we love all domain extensions equally, I’d be lying. Some domain extensions really resonated with us, while others simply didn’t. Unleash Your Inner Ninja!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unleash Your Inner Ninja! We love .ninja as a domain extension. It’s a fun extension, but it’s also one that we think people should like and use. It’s proving fairly popular too, with over 30 thousand .ninja domain names registered to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is .ninja for? Who should use one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than us telling you who we think should use a .ninja domain, why don’t you tell us why you’d use one? We can think of a lot of cool ways to use .ninja domains and have already secured what we consider to be one of the best .ninja domains around (more on that to follow soon)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, if you &lt;a href=&#34;http://member.intispace.com&#34;&gt;feel your inner ninja then why not register one today&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does SSL Protect My Website?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 17:12:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most economical and secure ways to protect your website on affordable hosting platforms is to deploy a private Secure Socket Layer (SSL) on you’re your website giving the instant ability to roll out protected URLs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysite.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.mysite.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still in doubt as to what an SSL actually does consider this explanation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symantec.com/theme.jsp?themeid=how-ssl-works&#34;&gt;Symantec&lt;/a&gt; on the digital handshake that takes place between a browser and a server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A browser attempts to connect to a website secured with SSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser requests that the web server identify itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends the browser a copy of its SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser checks whether it trusts the SSL certificate. If so, it sends a message to the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends back a digitally signed acknowledgement to start an SSL 7 encrypted session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypted data is shared between the browser and the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your site receives a permanent “security guard” which protects users in an online transaction, and encrypts data during transmission giving you, said Symantec, a “trillion year head start over a hacker.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At current computing speeds, a hacker with the time, tools, and motivation to attack using brute force would require a trillion years to break into a session protected by an SGC-enabled certificate,” said Symantec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To enable strong encryption for the most site visitors, choose an SSL Certificate that enables 128-bit minimum encryption for 99.9 percent of website visitors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are other benefits, too, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials establish identity online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication generates trust in credential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSL certificates on Intispace platforms are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed by Comodo, Geotrust, RapidSSL, Certum, Thawte, Symantec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99.3% compatibility with browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;256-bit encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lock appears in browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips For A Successful Business Blog</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/tips-for-a-successful-business-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 18:55:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/tips-for-a-successful-business-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;article id=&#34;post-7518&#34;&gt; &lt;section&gt;**A business blog can generate 126% more leads from potential customers, but how can you make it a success? Here are six top tips…**&lt;span id=&#34;more-7518&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The one thing the internet does is give everyone a voice.Tumblr alone has over 220 million blog accounts currently registered. [Almost a quarter of internet time][1] is spent either reading blogs or on social networks, and it’s been calculated that small businesses with their own blogs get [126%][2] more leads from potential new customers than blogless rivals.&lt;/p&gt; 

Unlike personal blogs, successful business blogs require planning and research as well as a long-term commitment to creating interesting and original content. Here are six guidelines to help ensure your blogs achieve your company’s long-term marketing goals and open up new audiences:

  * **Make it relevant.**

If your business is photography, blogging about your partner’s personal indiscretions or your political views won’t attract many new customers. Concentrate on your primary industry, but feel free to go off on tangents; a photographer could blog about Britain’s increasingly erratic weather, or why certain high street photography chains were rescued while other retailers went to the wall.

Having a clear objective from the outset will help to ensure that each blog achieves the predetermined objectives – some business bloggers want to boost their search engine rankings and increase their social media presence, while others simply want to sound authoritative. Study competitor blogs – what are they trying to achieve? What are they saying that’s different to you?

  * **Make it interesting.**

Online attention spans are very short, and there are myriad blogs competing for readers. Strong opinions and original perspectives are useful for engaging an audience, but so are detailed message-driven headlines, such as the ones [Disney Parks][3] use. A strong opening paragraph is crucial – particularly if it mentions current events. Always put the most important details first for maximum impact – tt gives a blog a ‘hook’ as newspapers call it. Many successful blogs like America’s [Southwest Airlines][4] use a combination of different media to maintain interest, from articles and surveys to photos and videos.

Images are a great way to add value to blogs. If you are imparting a piece of knowledge, then punctuate your posting with a suitable image. It gives the reader time to think about what you’ve said and also breaks up the text.

  * **Make it concise.**

Keep your blogs as short as your sentences. Opinions vary on the perfect length, but 300-400 words should be sufficient to convey a point. Use sub-headers and bullet points to break up the text, and try not to use more than one comma per sentence, but also be aware that the reader may not be following your thoughts so don’t be comma-phobic. From Vine to Flappy Bird, the internet is all about short bursts of intense content – business blogs should maintain this principle.

  * **Make it regular.**

To paraphrase an old sporting cliché, you’re only as good as your last blog. If that was published six months ago, you’re not very good at blogging. People who like your tone of voice or comments will expect regular updates, which will in turn keep your brand in the public eye and ensure you’ll be thought of when readers need your services. A blog a week should be the minimum target, particularly since search engines rank regularly-updated websites more highly than sporadically-updated ones. This is a key reason to host your blog on your corporate website, rather than on an external site like Blogger.

  * **Make it count with search engines.**

Many companies blog to improve their SEO rankings. If you run a small dairy, using the word “cheese” six times in each post can considerably improve your search engine results. Conduct Google Analytics tests to see which phrases people search for in your industry, and use some of these phrases (also known as long tail keywords) in each blog. Regularly review your ranking results through Google Analytics, or using rank-tracking tools like Moz.

  * **Make it interactive.**

There are numerous ways to make blogs interactive, from comments sections through to social media. Platforms like Facebook and LinkedIn encourage people to share content they like, so always post links to your work in case new readers discover you. Posting links to blogs through your company’s Twitter account or Google+ page also means less work creating original content for these platforms.

**Our [scalable WordPress hosting][5] makes sure your business blog is accessible from all devices, with our responsive editor allowing you to preview your site in all formats. [Get started today][5]!**&lt;/section&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned From Presidential Candidates Slips</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/lessons-learned-from-presidential-candidates-slips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 18:49:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/lessons-learned-from-presidential-candidates-slips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;article id=&#34;post-1605&#34;&gt; &lt;section&gt;**We’ve already seen several cases of domain name abuse in the short span of the most recent United States Presidential Campaign. What are these candidates doing to counter the attacks?**&lt;span id=&#34;more-1605&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The United States won’t elect another president until November 2016, but the campaigns have already begun.&lt;/p&gt; 

A major part of the early presidential canvassing is developing a sturdy PR that will boost a candidate’s name and reputation to the top.

This can prove to be difficult for some, and isn’t helped when some candidates have inadvertently allowed internet trolls to hijack related domain names. It’s becoming a trend that whenever a candidate announces their campaign, a free-for-all battle begins for every relevant domain name.

**Ted Cruz for President**

The first candidate of the 2016 election to fall victim to domain name abuse was Republican Ted Cruz. When he announced his campaign in March, he failed to register the most obvious domain name possible: tedcruz.com. Unfortunately, the domain was snapped up by someone who wasn’t a big fan of Cruz’s proposal to change Obama’s current immigration reform. At the time of writing this article, tedcruz.com shows:

SUPPORT PRESIDENT OBAMA.

IMMIGRATION REFORM NOW!

This can obviously damage Ted Cruz’s campaign, especially considering the popularity of .com domain names. If you run a simple [WHOIS search][1] on tedcruz.com, the registrant contact information is set to private, most likely indicating that whoever owns the domain does not plan on giving it up to the real Ted Cruz anytime soon.

Cruz found another detractor had also registered TedCruzForAmerica.com and redirected it to healthcare.gov, another policy Cruz is trying to eliminate.

All is not lost though. Cruz did acquire [tedcruz.org][2], the domain he intends to use for the rest of his presidential campaign.

**Carly Fiorina uses humor to counter trolls**

Another candidate for the Republican party, Carly Fiorina, recently announced her 2016 campaign. On the same day she announced that she’d be running, a Fiorina opposer registered carlyfiorina.org (Carly previously owned the domain, [but let it lapsein 2014][3]).

Instead of using the domain name to promote Fiorina’s campaign, the troll created a site critiquing the layoffs Fiorina oversaw while she was CEO of Hewlett-Packard. The website reads:

“Carly Fiorina failed to register this domain. So I’m using it to tell you how many people she laid off at Hewlett-Packard. It was this many:

_30,000 frowny faces._ 

That’s 30,000 people she laid off. People with families.”

When Fiorina was asked on _Late Night with Seth Meyers_ about the domain name fiasco, she demonstrated with humor how easy it is to register a domain name:



She purchased SethMeyers.org and later bought chucktodd.org after being a featured guest on _Meet The Press_. She pointed both domains to her official campaign website, [carlyforpresident.com][4], just to show that anyone can easily buy a domain name and do as they wish with it. Fiorina has also registered CarlyFiorina.com and redirected it to carlyforpresident.com.

**Hillary Clinton**

Yet another presidential candidate failed to register relevant domain names. Democrat Hillary Clinton did not register HillaryClinton.net, which now redirects back to Carly Fiorina’s official campaign website. No one is sure who’s behind this particular case of domain name trolling, but Fiorina’s team has denied knowing anything about it.

**The lesson?**

If you’re running for President, secure every domain name that could possibly be linked to your name or campaign. It’s better to be safe than sorry. Ted Cruz and Carly Fiorina had to learn this the hard way.

This lesson of course ultimately leads back to [brand identity and protection][5]. When registering a domain name for your business, think about what your competition may be doing to harm your business plans. The best practice is to make sure that you register every domain name that could link back to your business.

If you don’t, you never know what a clever internet troll will do to damage your brand. Don’t fall victim to an expired domain name. Check the status of your domain name by contacting your registrar today.

**Contact** [**Intispace.com support**][6] **if you have any questions regarding domain name renewal.**

**Note: [Intispace.com][7] clients can check and renew their domain by accessing control panel.**

This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;

** **&lt;/section&gt; &lt;/article&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shifting To An Encrypted Internet</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/shifting-to-an-encrypted-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 18:59:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/shifting-to-an-encrypted-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two thirds of all North American internet traffic will be encrypted by 2016, according to a new report by Sandvine, the Canadian-based software company. The reason behind it? Netflix.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1596&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to more and more sites using HTTPS encryption to protect confidential user information such as credit card numbers and other personal data, the days of having every website on the internet encrypted may not be far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most visited sites is now making the switch to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/how-to-encrypt-everything-1586619248&#34;&gt;encrypted connection&lt;/a&gt;. Netflix has announced it will soon follow other internet giants such as Google and Amazon in making its services fully encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is HTTP and HTTPS encryption?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) is the method by which files are transferred throughout the World Wide Web. This protocol determines how browsers and web servers send information back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTPS adds protection to a typical HTTP. The additional ‘S’ is for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.westhost.com/blog/2015/02/11/what-is-ssl-and-do-i-need-it-for-my-site/#.VUuY6I5VhHw&#34;&gt;Secure Socket Layer (SSL)&lt;/a&gt;. This added layer encrypts all of the data that is sent between a browser and a server. In other words if a hacker were to look at the HTTPS-protected files being sent between a browser and a server, all they would see is lines of garbage code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This greatly protects a visitor if they’re submitting any personal information on a website. There is a trend of  some sites switching over to a HTTPS connection in order to up their level of security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know if the site you’re visiting is protected with SSL, take a look at the address bar. If you see a little green padlock or https:// before the web address, you’re on a site that is encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTPS around the web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandvine &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sandvine.com/pr/2015/4/30/sandvine-two-thirds-of-north-american-internet-traffic-will-be-encrypted-in-2016.html&#34;&gt;conducted research showing that&lt;/a&gt; 65% of the internet’s current traffic is not encrypted. This will all change once Netflix makes the change later this year. One of the leaders in streaming services already accounts for about one third of North America’s internet traffic, meaning the change will make the majority of traffic encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reed Hastings, CEO of Netflix, said, “[Netflix] is making the move to protect member privacy, particularly when the network is insecure, such as public WI-FI, and it helps protect members from eavesdropping by their ISP or employer, who may want to record our members’ viewing for other reasons.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a trend that most people predict will continue to grow. Google (including YouTube) already encrypts all of its pages, which accounts for a very large portion of the internet. Most e-commerce sites use HTTPS to protect their customers’ confidential information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CTO of Sandvine, Don Bowman, said, “The decision by leading applications to encrypt their traffic is great for subscribers because it ensures the content of their internet traffic remains private.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to see more business owners choosing to encrypt their sites. Although you generally have to pay a little extra for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/how-does-an-ssl-protect-my-website/&#34;&gt;SSL certificate,&lt;/a&gt; most agree that it’s well worth the price for the added protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great blog with SSL!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ccTLDs Current Trends</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/cctlds-current-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 12:26:40 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/cctlds-current-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country Code Top Level Domains, or ccTLDs, are expanding across the globe. CENTR takes a closer look at current trends surrounding ccTLDs.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;span id=&#34;more-1590&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CENTR, &lt;a href=&#34;https://centr.org/&#34;&gt;The Council of European National Top Level Domain Registries&lt;/a&gt;, states that European ccTLDs have passed 67 million registrations with a total growth of 0.7% last quarter in their latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://centr.org/system/files/share/domainwire_global_tld_stat_report_2015_q1.pdf&#34;&gt;DomainWire report&lt;/a&gt;. ccTLDs, or Country Code Top Level Domains, are web address endings reserved for a specific country, territory or sovereign state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example: Australia – &lt;strong&gt;.au&lt;/strong&gt;, Japan – &lt;strong&gt;.jp&lt;/strong&gt;, United Kingdom – &lt;strong&gt;.uk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some ccTLDs have a local presence requirement that states that in order to register a specific regional domain you must have a local address attached to the registration. Put simply, to register a .London you must have a London address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CENTR reports that they are responsible for 80% of all registered country code domains worldwide, totaling 135,455,695 domain names. The top 20 largest ccTLDs represent about 82% of ccTLD registration and 38% of all domain names, including generic TLDs like .com and .net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web address ending .tk (Tokelau) holds the largest total registrations at 28.6 million, almost doubling the second place ccTLD .de (Germany). Tokelau has a slight advantage on registrations due to no local presence requirements and low registration costs. China (.ch) is third in total ccLTD registrations with 11.7 million and .uk (United Kingdom) comes in at fourth with 10.6 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colombia leads in total growth in last quarter with 8.4% more registrations ending in .co. China holds second place with 4.1% and Italy in third with 2.0%. Total growth across domains as a whole is only at 1.3% showing that ccTLDs are quickly becoming a leader in registered domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local presence requirements do pose something of a disadvantage for nations with smaller populations than the heavily populated China or Russia, and CENTR devoted a portion of their report based on per capita statistics. Presently .nl (Netherlands) hold the most ccTLD domains per capita with 33 registrations for every 100 residents, and Switzerland’s ccTLD .ch is second with 24 registrations per 100 residents. Trailing behind are Denmark (.dk), Germany (.de) and the United Kingdom (.uk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DomainWire reported that total new domain registrations, including the popular .xyz, .club and .berlin show a total 33% growth disproving early skeptics that gTLDs would be a fad and quickly fade out of the domain industry. The CENTR report shows that unique web address endings are most likely here to stay so we might as well jump on board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Learned from The Domain Name Survey</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-we-learned-from-the-domain-name-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 10:18:07 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-we-learned-from-the-domain-name-survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Domain Name Association conducted a global survey to understand internet users’ thoughts and opinions regarding domain names. Check out the results below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the period of October – November 2014, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.researchnow.com/en-US.aspx&#34;&gt;Research Now&lt;/a&gt; conducted a survey for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedna.org/&#34;&gt;Domain Name Association.&lt;/a&gt; The Domain Name Association, or DNA, is a new non-profit global business association that represents the interests of the domain name industry. The DNA’s primary intent of the survey was to see what people around the world think of &lt;a href=&#34;http://newgtlds.icann.org/&#34;&gt;ICANN’s gTLD program. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedna.org/pr_20150204.php&#34;&gt;DNA&lt;/a&gt;, the survey was designed “to measure global attitudes about awareness, acceptance, preference and knowledge related to domain names.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey involved 5,000 internet users across 10 countries. It consisted of 31 questions and took about 12-16 minutes for respondents to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the survey, DNA tested top-level generic names (e.g. .com, .org); country codes (e.g. .us, .us), along with new generic top-level names (e.g. .press, .club).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the complete results from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://thedna.org/documents/Global_Domain_Name_Preferences_Survey-Domain_Name_Association-Feb2015.pdf&#34;&gt;Domain Name Association&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, read on for the general conclusions that we made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the most part, people around the world are open to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/03/a-glance-of-top-level-domains-and-subdomains/&#34;&gt;new gTLDs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although .com is still the preferred TLD in the US and UK, other gTLDs received a considerable amount of attention. This was also especially true in other countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in Australia, 33.9% of respondents said that they’d go to shoes.melbourne to purchase shoes online. This is compared to only 7.2% that would go to shoes.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This varies greatly in the US where only 14% prefer a new TLD over .com. The UK was close, with only 20% saying they’d rather have a new TLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that the relevance of the domain name extension is extremely important to internet users. For example, when respondents were asked: “Where would you go to pay bills online?”, 35% of the US respondents said onlinepayments.secure. The other options, other than onlinepayments.com, received very low responses at around 1%. This shows that .secure adds a sense of security and relevancy to what the user is doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Domain names are still relevant when browsing the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although search engines have changed the way we locate websites, 85% of respondents said that they enter the entire domain name in the address bar at least some of the time. Out of those surveyed, 94% said that they at least sometimes check the domain name before clicking on a search result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of internet users are not aware of the new gTLD program. In fact, 75% of respondents were either unaware or unsure of the expansion of domain names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the majority agreed that expansion is necessary. When asked if there should be more domain name and domain-name extension options, nearly 60% replied yes. In developing countries, the request for more domain name options was even higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked why new extensions would be welcome, over 50% replied that new web addresses in meaningful combinations will be easier to remember. In a similarly phrased question, over 50% said new domain name extensions will make it easier to obtain short memorable names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we learned from the survey&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey results confirm that expanding domain name options is a positive action for the internet’s growth. This will be absolutely necessary as more and more websites are created. Luckily the majority of internet users seem willing to adapt to the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, many of those interviewed actually preferred ccTLDs and gTLDs over a generic domain such as .com (with the exception of the US and the UK who still prefer .com for most instances).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding the results Kurt Pritz, Executive Director of the DNA, said, “These are important findings for the Domain-Name industry, indicating a bright future for all domain-name extensions. When Internet users generally become aware of the new domain options, we expect widespread acceptance and even eagerness to adopt them”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the domain name reselling business the survey produces great news. The number of domain names, whether generic or new, will only increase as time goes on. Be sure to look for which new domain names are the most successful in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;Intispace.com&lt;/a&gt; specializes in scalable wordpress hosting. Use these survey results to see which domain names you’re most interested in building website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glance Guide to DNS</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/a-glance-guide-to-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 10:04:36 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/a-glance-guide-to-dns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a quick behind-the-scenes tour of how DNS works to connect you to your desired webpage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet is no longer just a nice-to-have feature. It has become a significant part of our lives, with most people connecting to the internet every single day. Although millions of people are online at any given time, many don’t understand what is going on behind the scenes. When you enter something in the address bar, how does the browser know exactly where to go? DNS is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS stands for Domain Name System. Everything on the internet would crash if it weren’t for DNS’s intricate processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll begin by explaining what a domain is. The concept of domain names is fairly easy to grasp. Basically, a domain name is a unique name that identifies a website. Behind every domain name is an IP address that is made up of many different numbers. IP addresses, or Internet Protocol addresses, are how computers and servers communicate with each other. Once an IP address is located, a web browser can open the desired web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This long list of numbers is very difficult to remember, hence why we have a domain name to make it easier. For example, the IP address of the domain google.com is 173.194.40.167. You could copy and paste this IP address in your browser and you would be directed to google.com. However, this would be an extremely tedious and difficult task to remember this 11 number code every time you want to access google.com. Domain names have simplified this task for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another key point with domains is that the domain name is google.com, not just google. If you don’t type the .com, you are not going to arrive at google.com. The TLD, or Top Level Domain, is the .com (or .org, .uk, .net, etc.) part of a domain name. Without this, the server will not know where to look and the website will not be accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving onto DNS. Simply put, DNS is a worldwide system that translates these domain names (e.g. google.com) into IP addresses. Once your computer has the IP address, it can access the web page and you can begin to access content. At the end of every domain, there is a “dot” that we never see. Google.com is actually google.com.. This “dot” at the end of the domain tells your operating system exactly where to look for the Root name servers. Although we don’t have to type in this extra “dot”, it is necessary behind the scenes in order to find the right IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are going to run through how your computer can find the appropriate IP address and load a web page. We’ll break down the process in six “simple” steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s say you want to find &lt;a href=&#34;http://vps.net/&#34;&gt;vps.net&lt;/a&gt;. You type in the domain name and wait.  As you do this, your computer begins searching for the right IP address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the IP address is not saved in temporary storage, or cache, it looks to your router. Your router will do the same: it will search in its cache, and if it isn’t there it will look elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your router will look to its configured DNS server(s). If the IP address is not cached there, it will look to the Root name servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Root name server will recognize that your web page is a .com TLD, and will direct the DNS server to the .com servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The .com server can then direct the DNS server to the correct DNS server to retrieve records (the site’s web hosting provider). The records are then transmitted back to the computer and the browser can access the IP address and convert the coded files into a fully usable web page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The site’s DNS records should now be stored in your computer’s cache for easy access. How long it will be stored will depend on the TTL, or Time to Live. You can change your TTL settings depending on your preferences. Generally, they are set for 24 hours. Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://searchnetworking.techtarget.com/definition/time-to-live&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more details about TTL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These “simple” steps all take place faster than I can hit the spacebar on my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS is commonly referred to as the “phonebook” of the internet. All domains are registered in this phonebook, but by different companies. Web hosting can be seen as the link between your site and your future visitors. &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;Most web hosting companies will register your domain name and provide you with all the DNS information you need&lt;/a&gt;. That way, when your client tries to access your site, they go through the DNS process and are directed to your web hosting provider, who will have your site saved on their servers. From there, your client can access the site from the web hosting provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process may seem daunting and confusing (and yes, it is a bit complicated), but it is a fascinating process that goes on all day, every day. In fact, I used DNS multiple times while writing this post without even thinking about it. Every time I clicked in my address bar to look up a word or to find a link, DNS was hard at work to direct me to the correct IP address. DNS provides us with a fast online experience that doesn’t require much work on our part. Let’s give it up for DNS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is .xyz Rising Above Controversy</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/is-xyz-rising-above-controversy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 09:55:28 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/is-xyz-rising-above-controversy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The new .xyz domain name has been a huge hit, but it hasn’t come without first facing accusations. Where does .xyz stand now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1579&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of 2013, The Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) officially released the first wave of new gTLDs. Research shows that ICANN’s new program has been an overall success, and that the .xyz domain name extension in particular has stood out from the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick domain names refresher for you: gTLD stands for generic Top-Level Domain. A TLD is simply the ending portion of a domain name (think .com or .net). This extension is an easy-to-remember representation of an IP address, which directs your site’s visitors to the correct place (as orchestrated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/a-glance-guide-to-dns/&#34;&gt;DNS, the internet’s Domain Name System&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August of 2013, ICANN began to publish new TLDs, giving everyone more opportunities to find a domain name that benefits their business or personal projects. Although some are still skeptical about the program, the new gTLDs have helped millions to find their perfect domain names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question many have asked is whether or not .com and .net will eventually become obsolete. It’s hard to believe that the world’s most popular TLD – .com – will ever fall from the top. However, .xyz is becoming a popular choice for people and businesses around the world and can now be found in the web addresses of large businesses, personal blogs and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this article, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ntldstats.com/&#34;&gt;905,003 .xyz&lt;/a&gt; domain name extensions have been registered. This is much higher than 2nd and 3rd place, which are .网址 (.website in Chinese) at 348,808 and .science at 249,900. In addition to being the current most popular gTLD, it is also the fastest growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.xyz launched on June 2, 2014 and has seen nothing but constant growth; over 100,000 .xyz domain names were registered in its first month. Is .xyz Rising Above Controversy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like with all success stories, there’s a reason that .xyz has done so well at market…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network Solutions, a popular domain name registrar, ran a campaign that offered their customers a free .xyz domain name with every .com domain. This stirred up controversy in the domain name world as it led to inflation of the number of .xyz domains registered. Although the promotion only lasted 10 days, over 100,000 domain names were registered during this short timespan, accounting for a sizable portion of the 903,003 .xyz domains in evidence today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Negari, CEO of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gen.xyz/&#34;&gt;.xyz registry&lt;/a&gt;, claimed that nothing was done incorrectly when .xyz was released; every .xyz domain name was paid and accounted for. The young CEO pointed out that as a domain registry .xyz sells its domains at a fixed cost to domain registrars, and following this these registrars (such as Network Solutions) can resell their domains at whatever price they see fit. &lt;a href=&#34;http://domainnamewire.com/tag/daniel-negari/&#34;&gt;Negari has made it clear&lt;/a&gt; that nothing was done illegally or unethically for the popular gTLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll leave it up to you to decide whether or not Daniel Negari or Network Solutions crossed lines when introducing the .xyz domain name. But putting the controversy aside, .xyz has been a huge hit. Even if you disregard all of the .xyz domain extensions that Network Solutions has sold (or given away), it would still stand as the most popular new gTLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the reasons .xyz continues to be a hit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to remember&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works for any market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End of the alphabet – end of a domain name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crosses the language barrier around the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inexpensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abuse policy (the .xyz registry monitors spam and phishing efforts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rising in popularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Intispace, we think the most important reason for the popularity of .xyz domains is that they can work for any kind of business. Unlike other new gTLDs that only pertain to certain markets, .xyz can be used for anything. .xyz domain names are usually similarly priced as .com domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are seeing more .xyz examples popping up.  On the hit TV series &lt;em&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;, a tech company called Hooli creates a new division of projects. Their domain name? [&lt;strong&gt;The new .xyz domain name has been a huge hit, but it hasn’t come without first facing accusations. Where does .xyz stand now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1579&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of 2013, The Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN) officially released the first wave of new gTLDs. Research shows that ICANN’s new program has been an overall success, and that the .xyz domain name extension in particular has stood out from the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick domain names refresher for you: gTLD stands for generic Top-Level Domain. A TLD is simply the ending portion of a domain name (think .com or .net). This extension is an easy-to-remember representation of an IP address, which directs your site’s visitors to the correct place (as orchestrated by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/a-glance-guide-to-dns/&#34;&gt;DNS, the internet’s Domain Name System&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August of 2013, ICANN began to publish new TLDs, giving everyone more opportunities to find a domain name that benefits their business or personal projects. Although some are still skeptical about the program, the new gTLDs have helped millions to find their perfect domain names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question many have asked is whether or not .com and .net will eventually become obsolete. It’s hard to believe that the world’s most popular TLD – .com – will ever fall from the top. However, .xyz is becoming a popular choice for people and businesses around the world and can now be found in the web addresses of large businesses, personal blogs and everything in between.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing this article, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ntldstats.com/&#34;&gt;905,003 .xyz&lt;/a&gt; domain name extensions have been registered. This is much higher than 2nd and 3rd place, which are .网址 (.website in Chinese) at 348,808 and .science at 249,900. In addition to being the current most popular gTLD, it is also the fastest growing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.xyz launched on June 2, 2014 and has seen nothing but constant growth; over 100,000 .xyz domain names were registered in its first month. Is .xyz Rising Above Controversy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like with all success stories, there’s a reason that .xyz has done so well at market…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network Solutions, a popular domain name registrar, ran a campaign that offered their customers a free .xyz domain name with every .com domain. This stirred up controversy in the domain name world as it led to inflation of the number of .xyz domains registered. Although the promotion only lasted 10 days, over 100,000 domain names were registered during this short timespan, accounting for a sizable portion of the 903,003 .xyz domains in evidence today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel Negari, CEO of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gen.xyz/&#34;&gt;.xyz registry&lt;/a&gt;, claimed that nothing was done incorrectly when .xyz was released; every .xyz domain name was paid and accounted for. The young CEO pointed out that as a domain registry .xyz sells its domains at a fixed cost to domain registrars, and following this these registrars (such as Network Solutions) can resell their domains at whatever price they see fit. &lt;a href=&#34;http://domainnamewire.com/tag/daniel-negari/&#34;&gt;Negari has made it clear&lt;/a&gt; that nothing was done illegally or unethically for the popular gTLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll leave it up to you to decide whether or not Daniel Negari or Network Solutions crossed lines when introducing the .xyz domain name. But putting the controversy aside, .xyz has been a huge hit. Even if you disregard all of the .xyz domain extensions that Network Solutions has sold (or given away), it would still stand as the most popular new gTLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the reasons .xyz continues to be a hit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to remember&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Works for any market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;End of the alphabet – end of a domain name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crosses the language barrier around the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inexpensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abuse policy (the .xyz registry monitors spam and phishing efforts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rising in popularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Intispace, we think the most important reason for the popularity of .xyz domains is that they can work for any kind of business. Unlike other new gTLDs that only pertain to certain markets, .xyz can be used for anything. .xyz domain names are usually similarly priced as .com domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are seeing more .xyz examples popping up.  On the hit TV series &lt;em&gt;Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;, a tech company called Hooli creates a new division of projects. Their domain name?]&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hooli.xyz/&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt; You can even visit the website to see what the fictional ‘Hooli’ is supposedly up to. Keep your eyes open and you’ll begin to notice even more .xyz domain names around the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will a .xyz domain work for you? Whatever business you’re managing, a .xyz can be a perfect fit. If you’re a domain reseller, consider making .xyz domain names readily available to your clients. With .xyz, there really is no end in sight. Is .xyz Rising Above Controversy ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pick up your own .xyz domain name from&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intispace.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not try Outsmart Google’s Algorithm To Achieve Your SEO</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/do-not-try-outsmart-googles-algorithm-to-achieve-your-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 11:54:33 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/do-not-try-outsmart-googles-algorithm-to-achieve-your-seo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;section&gt;**Instead of trying to cheat the major search engines’ algorithms, come up with compelling content that reaches your audience. The SEO will follow.**&lt;/p&gt; 

Far too often businesses try to crack the SEO “code” in order to arrive at the number one spot on Google. However, with a continually changing algorithm and no guarantee for success, your best bet is to focus on your audience, not the search engine.

Google, along with other popular search engines such as Yahoo and Bing, attempt to reward sites that have compelling content that actually meet their visitors’ needs. The algorithms are designed to display the absolute best result for keywords that are entered into a search bar.

This isn’t to say that there aren’t little tweaks and adjustments that SEOs make in order to boost your search engine rankings. But when it really comes down to it some of the simplest changes to your site can greatly boost your web presence. We take a look at four details you can implement into your site’s plan to fit a search engine’s ever-changing mold:

**It starts with the framework**

The design and development of your site is crucial for achieving a [high SEO ranking][1]. This starts with how you lay out your site and ends with the final development. Building a crawl-friendly website that allows your user to easily navigate the site will drastically improve your site’s rankings.

Start by creating a sitemap and a wireframe. Don’t even consider developing the site until you have a firm design for your site that will allow for a smooth UX (User Experience). [Take a look at these other guidelines][2] you should follow when designing and developing your site.

If a search engine can’t navigate through your site, you will not achieve the rankings that you desire.

**Implement a blog**

There are many reasons to start a [blog for your business][3], and improving SEO is at the top of the list. You don’t have to be a world-renowned author to write intriguing blog posts. All you need is a passion for your subject matter and a desire to share some of your insights with your clients and visitors.

Having a blog that you frequently update (we suggest posting at least once a week) greatly increases the number of pages related to your site. Every post you publish creates another chance for a potential visitor to find your site.

As with all other SEO practices, focus on creating content that will apply to your audience. Write blog posts that your visitors can actually relate to. As you build a strong library of posts, and as you gain followers, you will be able to add more links, and outside blogs will start linking to you, eventually building a large network.

**Social Media**

Similar to having a blog, having your business on various social media platforms builds a network and adds to the number of sources a search engine can display for your business. Try searching for a business you’re familiar with and see how far down their Twitter or Facebook page appears on the SERP (Search Engine Results Page). Most likely it’s near the top.

Social media also gives you [a chance to interact with your clients][4]. Instead of paying thousands for advertising that reaches the wrong demographic, you’re displaying information that leads directly to those who are following you.

In addition to these benefits of social media, a Tweet that goes viral or a Facebook post that gets shared over 1000 times will build more links, eventually helping your rankings.

**Focusing on keywords and content**

We arrive back to what SEO is really about: creating content that your visitors actually want to see. The best way to do this is by including the keywords that your clients will be searching for.

[The role of keywords in SEO has changed][5] over the years, but there’s no arguing that they still affect how a user finds and views your site. If you’re not using the keywords that your audience is typing in, it’s unlikely that they’ll arrive at your site.

Possibly the best route for SEO success is defining your audience and finding the words that they will be searching for. [&lt;section&gt;**Instead of trying to cheat the major search engines’ algorithms, come up with compelling content that reaches your audience. The SEO will follow.**&lt;/p&gt; 

Far too often businesses try to crack the SEO “code” in order to arrive at the number one spot on Google. However, with a continually changing algorithm and no guarantee for success, your best bet is to focus on your audience, not the search engine.

Google, along with other popular search engines such as Yahoo and Bing, attempt to reward sites that have compelling content that actually meet their visitors’ needs. The algorithms are designed to display the absolute best result for keywords that are entered into a search bar.

This isn’t to say that there aren’t little tweaks and adjustments that SEOs make in order to boost your search engine rankings. But when it really comes down to it some of the simplest changes to your site can greatly boost your web presence. We take a look at four details you can implement into your site’s plan to fit a search engine’s ever-changing mold:

**It starts with the framework**

The design and development of your site is crucial for achieving a [high SEO ranking][1]. This starts with how you lay out your site and ends with the final development. Building a crawl-friendly website that allows your user to easily navigate the site will drastically improve your site’s rankings.

Start by creating a sitemap and a wireframe. Don’t even consider developing the site until you have a firm design for your site that will allow for a smooth UX (User Experience). [Take a look at these other guidelines][2] you should follow when designing and developing your site.

If a search engine can’t navigate through your site, you will not achieve the rankings that you desire.

**Implement a blog**

There are many reasons to start a [blog for your business][3], and improving SEO is at the top of the list. You don’t have to be a world-renowned author to write intriguing blog posts. All you need is a passion for your subject matter and a desire to share some of your insights with your clients and visitors.

Having a blog that you frequently update (we suggest posting at least once a week) greatly increases the number of pages related to your site. Every post you publish creates another chance for a potential visitor to find your site.

As with all other SEO practices, focus on creating content that will apply to your audience. Write blog posts that your visitors can actually relate to. As you build a strong library of posts, and as you gain followers, you will be able to add more links, and outside blogs will start linking to you, eventually building a large network.

**Social Media**

Similar to having a blog, having your business on various social media platforms builds a network and adds to the number of sources a search engine can display for your business. Try searching for a business you’re familiar with and see how far down their Twitter or Facebook page appears on the SERP (Search Engine Results Page). Most likely it’s near the top.

Social media also gives you [a chance to interact with your clients][4]. Instead of paying thousands for advertising that reaches the wrong demographic, you’re displaying information that leads directly to those who are following you.

In addition to these benefits of social media, a Tweet that goes viral or a Facebook post that gets shared over 1000 times will build more links, eventually helping your rankings.

**Focusing on keywords and content**

We arrive back to what SEO is really about: creating content that your visitors actually want to see. The best way to do this is by including the keywords that your clients will be searching for.

[The role of keywords in SEO has changed][5] over the years, but there’s no arguing that they still affect how a user finds and views your site. If you’re not using the keywords that your audience is typing in, it’s unlikely that they’ll arrive at your site.

Possibly the best route for SEO success is defining your audience and finding the words that they will be searching for.][6] is a great resource for helping you find the keywords that you should include in your content. Once you know what your customers are actually searching for, you can refine your content to meet those needs.

Rather than spending time trying to crack the so-called “Google code”, try focusing on creating a site that contains compelling and linkable content. Search engines strive to determine which site will fit your customers’ needs. Create a content plan that fulfills these needs, eventually leading your site to the top of the SERP. Keep checking the [intispace blog][7] for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.

Also, send us a tweet [@intispace][8] with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!

&amp;nbsp;

This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here [www.intispace.com][9]&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
