<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Web Design on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/tags/web-design/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 01 May 2015 02:17:09 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Does Your About Us Page Really Say?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-does-your-about-us-page-really-say/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 02:17:09 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-does-your-about-us-page-really-say/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The ‘About Us’ page seems simple enough: tell your customers about your company and what it does. Learn how to effectively send an appropriate message to your visitors, and encourage them to give you business.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1427&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, an ‘About Us’ page seems easy to write and self-explanatory. However, far too often the page turns into corporate speak that relays nothing of importance to the targeted audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no definitive rules about what you should and shouldn’t include on your ‘About Us’ page. This is entirely dependent on your audience and the type of business you’re running. However, we have compiled a few failsafe tips that you can follow in order to create compelling content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are five ways to improve your ‘About Us’ page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 1. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Speak To Your Audience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any piece of content that you write, focus on your audience. Ask yourself the following questions: Who will be reading this page? How much do they already know about my company? Are they interested in this and that? What would they rather not know?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a few minutes to create a persona in your head. What do they actually want to take away from your ‘About Us’ page? Asking these simple, yet informative questions will give you the insight you need to include this and leave that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, you’re not writing this for yourself. You’re writing this &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://about.nike.com/&#34;&gt;Nike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uk2.net/about-us/&#34;&gt;UK2.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 2. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Use appropriate language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explain in simple terms how your business works. Include a description of what you do and how your organization is run. Visitors truly want to know what type of business you’re running. Use language that your audience will understand and relate to. Avoid too much industry jargon that you wouldn’t use in an everyday situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your ‘About Us’ page should be conversational. What would you want to tell a potential client if you were given a face-to-face opportunity? This is essentially what you’re doing, only in an online setting. Use your authentic voice and avoid using too many buzzwords that mask who you really are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apptopia.com/about&#34;&gt;Apptopia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Tell A Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of detail you include about your story will vary greatly depending on your business. A small local business can really benefit from telling its story. &lt;a href=&#34;http://moz.com/about&#34;&gt;Giving an account&lt;/a&gt; of how you got started and describing your experience in the field will help your visitors know that you are a real person and not some kind of automated business that lacks a personality. People want to do business with people, not corporations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every business has a story. What’s yours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.traveloka.com/careers&#34;&gt;Traveloka&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://moz.com/about&#34;&gt;The Moz Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; 4. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Show, Don’t Tell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any bit of persuasive writing, using large words to talk yourself up has little effect. Instead, use facts to describe what you’ve done. Include real testimonials to show that you have numerous satisfied customers. Any business can use words like ‘visionary’ or ‘cutting-edge’. Show that your business is different and actually focuses on satisfying clients’ needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have real facts to include, don’t make them up. Be sincere and talk about what your plans are for the future and how you’re going to achieve them. Customers love sincerity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/about&#34;&gt;tumblr.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativemarket.com/about?utm_source=CMblog&amp;amp;utm_medium=link&amp;amp;utm_campaign=CreativeAboutPages&#34;&gt;Creative Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;You’re Never Finished&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘About Us’ page is never really complete. As you gain experience and learn new things within your business, update your site. Minor tweaks to your ‘About Us’ page will keep your clients up to date with what’s going on right now. If we asked you about your company right now, would your ‘About Us’ page match what you’d tell us face to face?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Statistically this is one of the most visited pages on a site. Potential clients genuinely want to know what kind of business they’re getting involved with. It can often be a deal-breaker about whether they trust you enough to do business with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*This is one area of your site that you do not want to just brush over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
