<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Wordpress on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/categories/wordpress/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 10:14:18 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIP DAVID BOWIE</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2016/01/rip-david-bowie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 10:14:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2016/01/rip-david-bowie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“And the internet now carries the flag of being subversive and possibly rebellious, and chaotic and nihilistic….I think the potential of what the Internet is going to do to society both good and bad is unimaginable. I think we’re on the cusp of something exhilarating and terrifying.”&lt;/em&gt; – David Bowie, 2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIP DAVID BOWIE, To say that David Bowie was a pioneer was an understatement.  Not only did he redefine music and culture in a way never seen before or since — he even defined how technology was being used to spread culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know the gender-bending costumes and far out stories he told in his songs, but did you know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jan/11/david-bowie-bowienet-isp-internet&#34;&gt;David Bowie was an internet mogul too&lt;/a&gt;?  He was the first major artist to do an online-only distribution of a song back in 1996. Before sending tweets or liking a YouTube video, you could join BowieNet, which would allow you to chat with the artist, share links, and even launch your own web page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Bowie understood that the internet was not just bits and bytes, but a communication channel that connected people in ways never seen in history. He saw how disruptive it was to cultures around the world. Only years later would we all see Bowie’s vision unfold to shape not only music, but all future human interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIP DAVID BOWIE, Thank you for your vision and inspiration to us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/FACTmagazine/videos/10153819928364687/&#34;&gt;interview of David Bowie&lt;/a&gt; discussing the power of the internet back in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy ways to create a sitemap</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/08/easy-ways-to-create-a-sitemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 09:07:42 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/08/easy-ways-to-create-a-sitemap/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-a-sitemap&#34;&gt;What is a sitemap?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sitemap is a document that lists all URLs of your website that you would like crawled by a search engine. Most often, this document gives additional details such as the date a page was last modified, how frequently a page may change, and whether the page should be given priority over others, I will show you all the easy ways to create a sitemap..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-do-i-need-a-sitemap&#34;&gt;Why do I need a sitemap?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all become accustomed to using a search engine, probably daily. We often “Google” our questions throughout the day. Sitemaps are important because they tell search engines what pages are available for crawling on the website. They help search engines navigate your website and with this, your content is indexed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be wondering how sitemaps work, since it is kind of an abstract concept. Think of it this way, your website is a building, and the sitemap is the blueprint that explains where all the parts of the structure are. An important addition to any site, they are easy to create and once they are set up, do not require a lot of maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-the-search-engines-find-the-sitemap&#34;&gt;How do the search engines find the sitemap?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once your sitemap is set up, search engines don’t automatically find it. To have your site indexed, a submittal process is required. The process is easy, and this can be accomplished in just a few simple steps. There are others, but the two major search engines to start with are Google and Bing. Easy ways to create a sitemap, once you have your sitemap ready, you can do this by setting up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Webmaster Tools&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com/toolbox/webmaster&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bing Webmaster Tools&lt;/a&gt; account. After the accounts are setup, you will be able to walk through step by step to get your sitemap submitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-create-a-sitemap&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to create a sitemap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;small-website-solution-manual-option&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small website solution manual option&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xml-sitemaps.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;XML-Sitemaps&lt;/a&gt; is a tool that will generate a sitemap for you. Currently, it will generate up to 500 pages. This option works best for small websites that are not updated frequently since it requires manual updating each time a page is added or removed. It’s worth mentioning in case your preference is to be up and running quickly and don’t mind doing the manual work of creating and moving the sitemap file. If you want to create something fast, or are just curious about what a sitemap looks like, it is easy to generate one. All you have to do is enter your URL and it takes care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-12277&#34; src=&#34;http://getflywheel.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/xml-sitemap-generator.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;xml-sitemap-generator&#34; width=&#34;1022&#34; height=&#34;272&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the generator has created your sitemap, you need to upload it to the root of your domain; the URL will be something like www.yoursite.com/sitemap.xml.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;wordpress-specific-solutions-for-sitemaps&#34;&gt;WordPress specific solutions for sitemaps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know how awesome WordPress is and that there are many great plugins available. Although there is nothing wrong with manually creating a sitemap, it can be a pain if you have to do this all of the time. With sitemap specific plugins, there is no need to manually create your own. Although there are many options (and opinions!) out there, these two have been chosen as great options for an automatic solution to get you up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yoast’s WordPress SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may already be using WordPress SEO by Yoast. If so, it does have a sitemap generator built right into it. It is very easy to setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-12278&#34; src=&#34;http://getflywheel.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/yoast-plugin.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yoast-plugin&#34; width=&#34;1022&#34; height=&#34;1266&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will see an extensive option list that can be customized to your liking. If there are specific post types and taxonomies that you would like excluded, that is an option. If you have a very large site, Yoast has the capability to only include the specified number of URL’s listed on a page, which is less strain on your server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice thing is, this plugin takes care of the generating and publishing of the sitemap. It will be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yoursite.com/sitemap_index.xml&#34;&gt;http://www.yoursite.com/sitemap_index.xml&lt;/a&gt;. The main sitemap page lists a sitemap for each post type. It lists all the URLs that you would like crawled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google XML Sitemap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org/plugins/google-sitemap-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google XML Sitemaps&lt;/a&gt; is another great option. Google XML Sitemaps gives you extra information like details of when your sitemap was last generated, and it also has the capability to calculate the priority for each post by looking at the number of comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-12275&#34; src=&#34;http://getflywheel.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/google-xml-sitemaps.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;google-xml-sitemaps&#34; width=&#34;1022&#34; height=&#34;653&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does require a bit of setup to get up and running. The main settings page has options so you can create the perfect sitemap. Most of the configuration settings can be modified on this same page. Like Yoast, you can easily choose what to exclude. In addition to choosing the number of posts that are listed, you can increase the memory limit and execution time for the sitemap creation process, making this a flexible option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plugin will publish and update the sitemap automatically, so once things are set up, you do not have to do anything else, that easy ways to create a sitemap by default, this is the path to the sitemap: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yoursite.com/index.xml&#34;&gt;http://www.yoursite.com/index.xml&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a good practice to have a sitemap, and as an extra motivator, it’s worth mentioning the fact that there are SEO benefits to having one. On your journey to sitemapping, you will find that there are easy options for creating a sitemap, including great WordPress specific plugins that update and grow along with your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Few Tips For Your New Website</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 10:00:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/few-tips-for-your-new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you launch your brand new website, make sure you take these quick tips into account.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1737&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few tips for your new website, creating a new website can be a lot of work. Between coming up with a design, building the site (or hiring a developer) and marketing the new idea, you’re putting in several hours to ensure that your site will draw in new visitors while keeping the current ones engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you hit these targets  to increase customer engagement with your new website:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile-friendly design.&lt;/strong&gt; 64% of Americans now have a smartphone, and most of them are using them to access the internet on a daily basis. Make sure your site is easily accessible and navigable from a mobile device. Not only is it important to create a smooth browsing experience for mobile users, Google now actually penalizes sites that aren’t deemed “mobile friendly”. Make sure mobile-friendly design is at the top of your list. We suggest looking at responsive web design for best results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call to action.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t simply want your visitors going to your site, admiring the good design, and leaving. You want them to take action. Make sure you include a strong Call To Action (CTA) on your homepage. Make your CTA obvious and simple to follow. Your visitors should find it easy to sign up for your newsletter, make a purchase or give you feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved usability.&lt;/strong&gt; Your site should be visually appealing, but that counts for nothing if your visitors can’t find their way around your site. Usability is key when trying to keep your visitors on your site. To improve usability, make sure you consider your audience when designing your site. Will they know where to click next? Are you answering their questions? Will they be frustrated with anything on the site? Your visitors will leave right away if they’re confused about your site’s layout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Less is more.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t go overboard with excessive design. Think about usability first, and then make your site appealing to the eye. By using the right typography for your brand, tying in a consistent color scheme and including images that send the right message, you’re on your way to an effective, user-friendly design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Informative ‘About Us’ page.&lt;/strong&gt; Let your visitors know exactly who you are and what kind of values your business has. An ‘&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/what-does-your-about-us-page-really-say/&#34;&gt;About Us’ page should be informative and honest&lt;/a&gt;; people love seeing what really lies at the core of a company. If you’re a well-established business, display some of your accomplishments throughout the years. If you’re an up-and-coming startup, outline some of your goals for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compelling copy.&lt;/strong&gt; This goes back to finding your audience and talking directly to them. Now that someone has arrived at your site, pitch them your message! Copy should sound convincing, but you never want to come off as too salesy or intrusive. Be conversational and provide the answers that they’re searching for (that’s why most people are online – to get answers!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When in doubt, A/B test!&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes there’s no way of knowing which design will perform best. When launching your site, try a few different designs and see which one produces optimal results. This way, there is no doubting which design will work better for your site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed up your site.&lt;/strong&gt; There’s almost nothing that will drive away your visitors more quickly than &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/&#34;&gt;slow loading times&lt;/a&gt;. In fact, 40% of people say they will leave a page if it takes longer than 3 seconds to load. Check out this blog post to see how you can easily speed up your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAKE SURE YOUR MOVERS ARE PROFESSIONALS</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/make-sure-your-movers-are-professionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 09:22:48 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/07/make-sure-your-movers-are-professionals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever had to move, you know how difficult it can be. It doesn’t matter if you’re moving your website to a new host or your family to a new house. Even if your current location causes you a lot of stress, the pain of moving somewhere new can make it seem worthwhile to stay in a place you’re not happy. Moving doesn’t have to be a massive difficulty for you, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My old friend, Christian Dubois moved his houses earlier this week. To help alleviate the pain, he hired professionals. He did research on moving companies, discovering that many hire part-time or seasonal employees. That terrified him. Some people may say stuff is just stuff, but it’s my stuff and much of it is very important to me. He was hiring professionals to reduce his stress, not simply replace it with the worry that inexperienced movers might break things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving hosting sucks, make sure your movers are professionals. When people move from an old host to Intispace, we know the process can be stressful. No one wants to escape a bad host only to find their website doesn’t work properly on the new one. That’s why we train our expert staff to move people safely and effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s your home, your business, or your website, moving sucks. Working with trusted professionals like Intispace lets you relax while they take care of all the heavy lifting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Optimization, An Easy Win For A Faster Site</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/image-optimization-an-easy-win-for-a-faster-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:05:27 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/image-optimization-an-easy-win-for-a-faster-site/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Website speed optimization can be a complex and technical practice, but the non-techies out there will be happy to learn that one of the biggest problems is actually easy for the layperson to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-with-images&#34;&gt;The Problem With Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Optimization, An Easy Win For A Faster Site. Images are typically the one of the biggest drains on page load time. Even with caching and a CDN, an unoptimized image will still drag down your page loading time. But, as the website owner, images are completely under your control, so if you can get a handle on how to work with and optimize images, you can have a great impact on the speed of your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the websites that I look at during my Intispace customer support duties, I see that images contribute, on average, about 30% of the total page load time. Often this is the single largest factor of the loading time. In extreme cases, it could be closer to 60% of the loading time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example of what un-optimized images will do to your site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-431  lazyautosizes lazyloaded&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/pingdom-image-slow-site.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Large Images slow down your website&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;108&#34; data-lazy-src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/pingdom-image-slow-site.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The load time is 12 seconds and the size of the page is 8MB. Of those 8MB, images account for 6.7MB. This is out of control!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of http requests is commonly cited as a factor in load time, and while it is important, ultimately it’s the page size that is the real indicator of speed or slowness. You can have a small number of http requests, but if those requests are summoning giant images, you will have a problem on your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-dimensions-and-file-size&#34;&gt;Understanding Dimensions and File Size&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dimensions of the image, i.e. how much space on the screen an image takes up, are measured in pixels and while they do not 100% dictate file size, they are related. The larger the dimensions of your image, the larger the file size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File size is measured in kilobytes (KB) and megabytes (MB)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1MB = 1000KB&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a point of reference, the main content column of this blog is 796 pixels wide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take a photo with your smartphone, depending on your settings, that photo could be in the region of 2500 pixels wide (or even more) with a filesize of 3MB (or 3000KB). If I were to take a photo with my phone and upload it to this blog without any editing, I’m going to be uploading a file that is about 3 times as big as it needs to be – a total waste of resources and a drag on page load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while snapping phone pics and uploading to your blog might be simple, it creates a real problem if you want a fast site,  by adding tons of unnecessary weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;resizing-images&#34;&gt;Resizing Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the first thing you need to do is resize your images to the correct size for your site. For blog images, figure out how wide your blog’s content area is  and never upload an image wider than that. If it’s going to be used in a slider, make sure you determine the dimensions of the slider first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you know how wide your content area is?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know how to use the developer tools built in to Chrome or Firefox, you can use that. But if that sounds scary there are simpler tools available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on a Mac, there is a screen capture tool, Grab, already built-in, and when you outline an area on the screen it will tell you the pixels. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aeyoun.com/posts/osx-screen-shot-ruler.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;This article explains in more detail.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can  &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/page-ruler/jlpkojjdgbllmedoapgfodplfhcbnbpn/related?hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;install the easy Page Ruler addon  for Chrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve figured out what dimensions your images should be, you can use any of the below tools to resize your images accordingly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resizing Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIMP – free, Windows &amp;amp; Mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irfan View- free for Windows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preview for Mac – it’s already installed!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers on Macs can &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/sips.1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;check out sips, a command line tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Tools For Resizing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picmonkey.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pixlr.com (also has mobile app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fotor.com (also has mobile app)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter which one you use – all you need to do is locate the resize feature. You’ll be able to enter the desired pixel width and the application will make sure the image stays in proportion by adjusting the height automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;image-formats&#34;&gt;Image Formats&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Images on the web should be saved in either .jpg, .png, or possibly .gif&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JPEGs&lt;/strong&gt; are best used for photographs and general purpose images where you do not need any transparency. You can compress them easily and get a smaller filesize suitable for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PNGs&lt;/strong&gt; will often generate a larger filesize so should only be used when you have an image that requires transparency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GIFs&lt;/strong&gt; are less frequently used. They have a limited range of color so can only be used for very simple images, but can produce a small filesize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;compressing-images&#34;&gt;Compressing Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’ve dealt with the physical dimensions of the image, now let’s deal with the ‘weight’ of the image. We want to compress the image to make it as lean and fast-loading as possible. &lt;strong&gt;The goal is to reduce the filesize&lt;/strong&gt;. There isn’t a magic number as to what each image should be, since it depends on how the image will be used. Images being used in a hero banner or slider will be bigger, but if you have a few of them, I’d aim to get each one down to 100KB or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Small images that are going to be used for thumbnails, logos etc will be much much smaller. The logo at the top of this blog, for example, is 3.8KB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With compression there may be a slight loss in quality, so you’re looking for a balance between quality and file size. But always remember that the smaller the filesize, the faster the load time will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photoshop – make sure to use the &lt;em&gt;Save For Web&lt;/em&gt; option&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GIMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ImageOptim (Mac)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Tools&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compressor.io – make sure to choose the ‘lossy’ option for the biggest size reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wordpress-plugins&#34;&gt;WordPress Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s preferable to resize and compress your image before you upload it to WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if your site is already live, you will need to deal with the images that are already there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the crucial images such as logos, headers and others that load on every page of your site, it would be best to make new versions of the images as described above, then install the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/enable-media-replace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enable Media Replace plugin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This will allow you to simply replace existing images in your media library with the new, optimized ones, without breaking any links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the other images sitting in your media library, where it would be unrealistic to go through and fix them all individually,there are a few handy plugins that will help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/ewww-image-optimizer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EWWW Image Optimizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This plugin can go through your existing media library and compress everything in bulk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you build sites for clients or have a site with multiple users where you cannot ensure that everyone is using best practices and uploading nicely optimized images, the below plugins will help mitigate that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/imsanity/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Imsanity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can determine the settings so that if someone uploads a gigantic image, it will automatically be reduced to maximum size of your choosing. No more 4000 pixel images clogging up the media library!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/tiny-compress-images/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Compress JPEG &amp;amp; PNG Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once set up, this uses the TinyPNG API to automatically compress images on upload. You can get a free API key for up to 500 images/month which would be plenty for the average blogger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to benchmark the speed of your site, or do before/after comparisons with images after optimizing, &lt;a title=&#34;How To Correctly Measure Your Website’s Page Load Time&#34; href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/?p=33279&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;follow this guide on how to properly measure the load time of your site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Measure Your Website’s Page Load Time</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 00:00:04 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-to-measure-your-websites-page-load-time/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;When assessing the effectiveness of CDN, W3 Total Cache or any other WordPress caching plugin, it’s important that you are able to correctly measure the page loading time of your website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several tools available for How To Measure Your Website’s Page Load Time. Our favorite, and the one we think is most accurate, is Pingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-use-pingdom&#34;&gt;How To Use Pingdom&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert info&#34;&gt;
  Visit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.pingdom.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://tools.pingdom.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click Settings and choose the location closest to your web server, not your own physical location. Paste in your website URL and click Test Now.&lt;span id=&#34;more-283&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pingdom will summarize your web page performance at the top with 4 metrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance grade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-286  lazyautosizes lazyloaded&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/Website-speed-test-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pindgom website speed test&#34; width=&#34;639&#34; height=&#34;553&#34; data-lazy-src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/Website-speed-test-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these metrics, the most important is load time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grade is a general guideline of how well your site is optimized, but it’s not important to get a perfect score there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The speed at which your site loads is really the only number that matters. When Google is visiting your site, it does not care or know about the performance grade, only the loading time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-an-accurate-average&#34;&gt;Getting An Accurate Average&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should run the test several times to get an average loading time since it will not be identical every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have just added caching to your site, or have changed any options in your caching plugin, the first time a visitor (including a Pingdom bot) hits your page (unless it’s been preloaded), they will get a non-cached version of the page. That visit causes the cache to be generated, so the next visitor will get the faster, cached version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you run the speed test, the first result could possibly be on a non-cached version of your page which is why it’s important to run the test a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intispace + Cloudflare will preload the homepage of your site and the pages linked from it when you either manually click the Preload button, when the cache has expired or when you create or update a post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, when you create/update content the cache is deleted and preloaded a few seconds later for associated content such as category and tag archive pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you simply use the Clear Cache feature or just save the settings, the preload won’t get triggered. So either trigger it manually, or just visit your website to generate the cache.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people only test the homepage of their site which typically has a lot more content on it than a regular page or post. So consider testing various types of content on your site to get a more well-rounded view of how fast your site is as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On many websites, visitors finding the site from a search engine will enter your site on a blog post or individual page, not necessarily the homepage, so the performance of all pages needs to be fast. You’ll probably find that those internal posts/pages load faster than your homepage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;benchmarking&#34;&gt;Benchmarking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To really see how much improvement you’re getting from your caching plugin you need to benchmark your site without any caching plugins first by running the above tests and taking an average page load time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then add your caching plugin with its most basic configuration and run the tests a few more times to get a comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time you activate a new option in the plugin you need to see if it has an impact – for better or worse, so you need to test each change that you make, in the above manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people turn on W3 Total Cache for example and enable ALL the additional options but find some slowness. This could be because additional options such as minification and others have the potential to conflict with themes, plugins and server configurations and should be used cautiously. They are not always necessary. Just turning on the plugin will give you the most significant speed boost. The additional options are just that – optional. They are not always necessary and should always be tested to see if they are giving you additional improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing after every change lets you isolate a particular feature that may be causing an issue. This is true of W# Total Cache or any of the other caching plugins you may use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, make sure you don’t have multiple caching plugins running at once. For example, even if WP Super Cache is installed but not activated, it can still interfere so it needs to be fully deleted before testing a different plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-waterfall-chart&#34;&gt;The Waterfall Chart&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waterfall shows you the loading time of each component of your page – all the various image files, CSS, Javascript files etc that are loaded each time someone visits your page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using a caching plugin such as W3 Total Cache you should be getting a fast loading time, but the waterfall chart can help you identify any bottlenecks or problematic files. Sometimes it only takes a couple of large images or external scripts to drag down the loading time of your page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the dropdown at the top of the waterfall and choose “Sort By Load Time”. This will show you the longest loading files at the top, making problem files easy to spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External scripts such as those from third party ad servers etc are probably your biggest enemy here. Since those scripts are not coming from your server there is no caching you can do on them – you are at the mercy of their server. You can see that in this example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-285 aligncenter  lazyautosizes lazyloaded&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/sort-by-load-time.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pingdom - Sort By Load Time&#34; width=&#34;639&#34; height=&#34;114&#34; data-lazy-src=&#34;http://cdn.wp-rocket.me/wp-content/uploads/4/sort-by-load-time.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash Your Inner Ninja!</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/unleash-your-inner-ninja/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:35:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/unleash-your-inner-ninja/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been posting sporadically about various new domain extensions over the last year and we currently offer a very large (and growing) selection. While I’d love to say that we love all domain extensions equally, I’d be lying. Some domain extensions really resonated with us, while others simply didn’t. Unleash Your Inner Ninja!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unleash Your Inner Ninja! We love .ninja as a domain extension. It’s a fun extension, but it’s also one that we think people should like and use. It’s proving fairly popular too, with over 30 thousand .ninja domain names registered to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is .ninja for? Who should use one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than us telling you who we think should use a .ninja domain, why don’t you tell us why you’d use one? We can think of a lot of cool ways to use .ninja domains and have already secured what we consider to be one of the best .ninja domains around (more on that to follow soon)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, if you &lt;a href=&#34;http://member.intispace.com&#34;&gt;feel your inner ninja then why not register one today&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intispace Platform Improvements, And How You Benefit</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/intispace-platform-improvements-and-how-you-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 13:43:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/intispace-platform-improvements-and-how-you-benefit/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;One of our goals here at Intispace is to continue innovating and improving our platform so you can get the absolute most out of it. And late last year and early this year we made a host of intispace platform improvements to our platform that give all Intispace customers better performance, tighter security, and updated caching. Intispace Platform Improvements, And How You Benefit, Combined, these improvements result in faster, more reliable, and more secure WordPress sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a quick look at some of our recent platform improvements and how you benefit from them as a Intispace customer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;performance&#34;&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intispace Platform Improvements, And How You Benefit. We’re in the process of updating our platform to PHP 5.5, Ubuntu 14.04, and MySQL 5.6. These upgrades individually deliver huge performance gains, and when combined they can account for nearly a 50 percent increase in speed for our customers. Thousands of our customers have already been moved into the new platform, and all new customers are on this platform already.  We continue to actively migrate customers, and we’ll send you an email as part of the migration process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also improved our performance monitoring and our hotspot identification and now use it to actively drive performance improvements in our platform. Proactive performance monitoring helps us identify customers who may have performance issues. Our team digs in and finds the root cause of the issue and pushes the improvements upstream–into WordPress, plugins, or our platform, which benefits a larger set of customers and allows us to drive  improvements in the performance and scalability of third-party plugins. So far, this effort has resulted in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to the way we do object caching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to our baseline database configuration and schema&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several changes in third-party plugins to make them operate better at scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;security&#34;&gt;Security&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continue to improve our malicious traffic detection and blocking (web application firewall), which reduces overall server load and protects your WordPress sites from attackers. The attacks that we block include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploits against several plugins, such as the RevSlider vulnerability, that attempt unauthorized downloads of php files, configuration files, /etc/passwd, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attempts to gain unauthorized access to wp-admin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This improvement was put into action recently and complete well before the public announcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;caching&#34;&gt;Caching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve also improved our caching for mobile sites by updating how our platform handles mobile search engine bots. Previously, mobile-specific bots could be served cached versions of non-mobile-optimized pages. This is an important improvement for sites that serve different content to mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These updates, and the updates we’re currently working on, reaffirm our commitment to all Intispace customers that we’ll continuously innovate and work on ways to intispace platform improvements&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say Goodbye to SSL Version 3.0</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/say-goodbye-to-ssl-version-3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 12:44:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/say-goodbye-to-ssl-version-3-0/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It is no secret that securing your client’s data is an ongoing process and not something that you can simply install on a server/platform. That is why security solutions and protocols evolve all the time and developers frequently release new versions. The two cryptographic protocols that provide communication security over the Internet are TLS and SSL. The latest version of Secure Sockets Layer (SSL version 3.0) is the predecessor of TLS and is nearly 15 years old. So it was only a matter of time for someone to find the next big issue related to the SSL protocol. Yesterday Bodo Möller from the Google Security Team wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://googleonlinesecurity.blogspot.co.uk/2014/10/this-poodle-bites-exploiting-ssl-30.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a blog post&lt;/a&gt; about a new vulnerability in the design of SSL version 3.0. The vulnerability allows attackers to calculate the plain text of secure connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-7162&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;possible-fixes&#34;&gt;Possible Fixes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two ways to protect yourself. The first and best way to mitigate this problem is to completely disable SSL version 3.0 on all of your servers and also remove SSL 3.0 support from all client products. For example, Google officially announced in the same blog post that in the coming months they will remove SSL version 3.0 support from all of their client products (including the Google Chrome browser). Cloudflare and Sucuri already stopped supporting it. All other major browsers will also disable SSLv3 by default (Firefox version 34 will be released on Nov 25).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second solution is to support &lt;a href=&#34;https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-ietf-tls-downgrade-scsv-00&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TLS_FALLBACK_SCSV&lt;/a&gt;. This is a solution which prevents attackers from tricking browsers to use the old SSLv3 protocol instead of the TLS protocol. However, this solution is difficult to implement (many people will need to manually compile custom version of openssl) and it is only a new patch which solves this issue but does not provide any guarantees that SSLv3 won’t become vulnerable again a week from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-solution&#34;&gt;Our Solution:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on a detailed analysis of our network and the traffic towards our servers we decided to completely remove SSL version 3.0 support. As a matter of fact, a big portion of our servers have already been configured to support only the TLS encryption protocol and we’re in the process of reconfiguring all machines that are part of our infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;possible-issues&#34;&gt;Possible Issues:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that some web applications still use SSLv3. Let’s say that for example a developer has decided to configure his/her PHP app to use SSLv3 via the CURLOPT_SSLVERSION option. Unfortunately, if such application connects to our servers, the connection will not be established and the developer will need to patch the code of the app. Our analysis shows that less than 0.05% of all traffic towards our servers is SSLv3. Thus, we do not expect such issues to occur, but we still encourage our customers to contact us via our Helpdesk if they notice any SSL-related issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Jetpack!</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/optimizing-jetpack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 12:35:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/optimizing-jetpack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;grid-col span12&#34;&gt;
  Jetpack remains a polarizing plugin amongst developers so it’s not often discussed on developer-oriented blogs. The plugin has a history filled with bloat, slowness, and conflicts with other plugins. Admittedly, I myself have a love/hate relationship with it.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;grid-col span12&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;grid-col span12&#34;&gt;
  However, recently, it’s been improved so much that I feel comfortable recommending it for some users. It’s now truly modularized, allowing complete control over which features are activated, and much more stable. My biggest pet peeve will always be the way you have to connect to WordPress.com to use it. I understand all the technical reasons for that, but it’s a terrible user experience that is very confusing (especially for novice WordPress users).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;grid-col span7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;post-content&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      With all that said, why is Optimizing Jetpack making an appearance here? The fact is if you can get past the clunky activation, Jetpack offers a great suite of features for the average blogger. But, in keeping with the WordPress philosophy of “decisions not options”, as an end user, you don’t have many configuration settings compared to all the options you would get if you used a similar standalone plugin.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Fortunately, the code has been sprinkled with actions and filters for developers. So, while Jetpack is generally marketed to entry-level end users, there are actually some nice Easter eggs for developers who want to customize things a little bit for their clients −I call them Easter eggs because the ability to customize Jetpack hasn’t really been highlighted or documented too much. There has yet to be a complete resource that documents all of filters and actions available (I’ll give just a few examples here), but you can dig through the code looking for add_filter and add_action to find more. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Automattic/jetpack&#34;&gt;code can be found on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; for easy reading (and if you want to contribute).
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      This article assumes you have some experience with development or at least are not afraid to work with code, even if it’s just copy/pasting snippets (hey, we all start out like that!). Here’s just a handful of ways you can tweak Jetpack.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Ditch That WordPress.com Connection…&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Optimizing Jetpack! …Well, almost. You can actually use Jetpack without connecting to WordPress.com, at least partially. Some of the modules will work fine without the connection whereas some will remain unavailable. This comes handy when you are working on a local installation or even a production site if you’re only using certain modules.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Add the following to your wp-config.php file to use development mode:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;define( ‘JETPACK_DEV_DEBUG’, true);&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;h4&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Customization Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Optimizing Jetpack! When customizing Jetpack, there are a couple of things to keep in mind:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Your customizations will generally be achieved by writing your own functions, so make sure to use &lt;strong&gt;unique function names&lt;/strong&gt; to avoid collision with any other plugin. I’ll prefix all mine with ‘wtwlb’ (wtw for WebTrainingWheels, lb for my initials) in these examples.
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Customizations can either be done in your theme, the child theme’s functions.php and template files, or via a ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://css-tricks.com/wordpress-functionality-plugins/&#34;&gt;functionality plugin&lt;/a&gt;’. This is a simple plugin that contains anything you would otherwise paste in functions.php and it is advantageous because it’s theme-independent. If you plan on using the Jetpack mobile theme and customizing it, you will need to do it this way.
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Customize The Sharing Module&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The sharing module in Jetpack is popular as it’s a pain-free way to add the most popular social share buttons to your content. Yet there are a couple of limitations.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Change Button Placement&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;By default, Jetpack lets you choose on what content (posts, pages, homepage, etc.) you want the buttons to appear, but it automatically places the buttons at the bottom of the content. A common request is to add the buttons at the top as well as (or instead of) at the bottom. This is really easy to do.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      The icons are placed using a filter on the WordPress tags for the_content and the _excerpt:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;add_filter( ‘the_content’, ‘sharing_display’, 19 );
 add_filter( ‘the_excerpt’, ‘sharing_display’, 19 );&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Removing either of those placements would be a matter of writing a small function to remove the appropriate filter. To remove it from the_content, and, therefore, from the bottom of the post, for example, the below would work:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;function wtwlb_remove_share() {
 remove_filter (‘the_content’, ‘sharing_display’, 19 ); }
 add_action (‘loop_start’, ‘wtwlb_remove_share’);&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Then you can use the following in your functionality plugin to place the buttons at the top of the post:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;function wtwlb_move_jpshare( $content = ” ) {
 if ( function_exists( ‘sharing_display’ ) ) {
 return sharing_display() . $content;
 }
 else {&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;return $content;
 }
 }
 add_filter( ‘the_content’, ‘wtwlb_move_jpshare’, 19 );&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      If you want to manually place the buttons elsewhere in your custom theme or child theme’s template files, you can use the following wherever you want the buttons to appear:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;if ( function_exists( ‘sharing_display’ ) ) {
 sharing_display( ”, true );
 }&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Remove the Counter&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Optimizing Jetpack! By default, Jetpack will show the sharing counts on the buttons. If you’d like to prevent that, you can do so with one line:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;add_filter( ‘jetpack_sharing_counts’, ‘__return_false’ );&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-14063&#34; src=&#34;http://s1.mt-cdn.net/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/markuppicture.png&#34; alt=&#34;markuppicture&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;314&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Style The Icons&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Optimizing Jetpack! There’s no fancy trick to styling Jetpack sharing buttons. You can radically change the look with pure CSS in your child theme. The icons themselves are Genericons (an icon font), making them easy to manipulate the color, size, etc.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h4&gt;
       &lt;strong&gt;Customize Related Posts&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Optimizing Jetpack! Showing related content is a great feature to keep readers on your site, but some WordPress plugins that do this can be slow and inefficient. Jetpack offloads the intensive processing work to its WordPress.com servers, allowing for a nimble Related Posts feature. By default, you only have two options to customize:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-14064&#34; src=&#34;http://s1.mt-cdn.net/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/customizerelatedposts.png&#34; alt=&#34;customizerelatedposts&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;295&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      So, here are a few handy tweaks you can make:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Customize the Number of Posts&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;By default, the module displays three posts. You can change that with the function below. For example, this will set the number of posts to four:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;function wtwlb_jpmore_related_posts( $options ) {
 $options[‘size’] = 4;
 return $options;
 }
 add_filter( ‘jetpack_relatedposts_filter_options’, ‘wtwlb_jpmore_related_posts’ );&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Since I want four posts in a row and the module style is based on three, I’ll need to tweak the CSS to accommodate. Here I set the width of each to 25% instead of 33%:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;div#jp-relatedposts div.jp-relatedposts-items .jp-relatedposts-post {
 width: 25%;
 }&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;div#jp-relatedposts div.jp-relatedposts-items .jp-relatedposts-post:nth-child(3n+4),
 div#jp-relatedposts div.jp-relatedposts-items-visual .jp-relatedposts-post:nth-child(3n+4) {
 clear: none;
 }&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Change the Headline&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;The default headline for the related posts section is simply “Related”. In this snippet, we’ll change that to “Recommended Posts”:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;function wtwlb_related_posts_headline( $headline ) {
 $headline = sprintf(
 ‘&amp;lt;h3 class=”jp-relatedposts-headline”&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;%s&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;’,
 esc_html( ‘Recommended Posts’ )
 );
 return $headline;
 }
 add_filter( ‘jetpack_relatedposts_filter_headline’, ‘wtwlb_related_posts_headline’ );&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      This is how it looks by default:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-14069&#34; src=&#34;http://s1.mt-cdn.net/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/headlinechange.png&#34; alt=&#34;headlinechange&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;552&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      And with the two changes above:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-14070&#34; src=&#34;http://s1.mt-cdn.net/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/twochangesheadline.png&#34; alt=&#34;twochangesheadline&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;294&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Change Thumbnail Size&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;If you’d like to change the dimensions of the thumbnails that go with each related post, you can use the following. In this example, I’m making the images square, i.e. 125 x125:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;function wtwlb_jp_image_size ( $thumbnail_size ) {
 $thumbnail_size[‘width’] = 125;
 $thumbnail_size[‘height’] = 125;
 return $thumbnail_size;
 }
 add_filter( ‘jetpack_relatedposts_filter_thumbnail_size’, ‘wtwlb_jp_image_size’ );&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      You can find a slew of other tweaks like this here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://jetpack.me/support/related-posts/customize-related-posts/&#34;&gt;http://jetpack.me/support/related-posts/customize-related-posts/&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;h4&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Customize The Mobile Theme&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;/h4&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      The mobile theme included in Jetpack is clean and functional, but, again, a little short on options. It’s not going to look like your desktop theme right out of the box, but it can be styled quite easily.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Create Custom Mobile Styles&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;There are a couple options to apply styling to the mobile theme. Remember, because it’s a separate theme, you cannot add your styling to your regular desktop theme style.css because that’s not going to be loaded on mobile.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        For an easy way to include custom CSS, I like to use a plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/simple-custom-css/&#34;&gt;Simple Custom CSS&lt;/a&gt;. It just provides a box for you to enter your CSS and have it apply regardless of the theme. It’s perfect for these sort of cases. To target styles specifically within the mobile theme, just make sure to use the class: .mobile-theme
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Create a separate style sheet and enqueue it. This could be particularly useful if you want to keep your custom CSS out of the dashboard where an over-zealous client might get their hands on it.
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Here’s the code you’d need to do that:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;// Check if we are on mobile
 function jetpackme_is_mobile() {&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;// Are Jetpack Mobile functions available?
 if ( ! function_exists( ‘jetpack_is_mobile’ ) )&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;return false;&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;// Is Mobile theme showing?
 if ( isset( $_COOKIE[‘akm_mobile’] ) &amp;&amp; $_COOKIE[‘akm_mobile’] == ‘false’ )
 return false;&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;return jetpack_is_mobile();
 }&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;// On mobile? Enqueue your custom style sheet
 if ( jetpackme_is_mobile() ) {
 add_action( ‘wp_enqueue_scripts’, ‘wtwlb_jetpackme_mobile_css’ );
 }&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;// Build the function
 function wtwlb_jetpackme_mobile_css() {&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;wp_enqueue_style( ‘mobile-style’, plugins_url( ‘mobile-style.css’, __FILE__ ), array(‘style’), ‘1’, ‘all’ );
 }&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      In this case, I have created a mobile specific style sheet called mobile-style.css, which will be saved in the same folder as my functionality plugin.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Mobile Specific Widgets&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Optimizing Jetpack! Presently, there isn’t an elegant way to have mobile-specific widgets using the Jetpack mobile theme. But here’s a method that will work.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      By default, the mobile theme will look in your main theme for a sidebar registered with the ID: sidebar-1 and it will use that at the bottom of your mobile theme. If your theme does not have a sidebar with that ID, you won’t have any widgets unless you register one for this purpose.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Assuming you do have that sidebar, by default all widgets in it will show on mobile. But if you want to control that and only show certain ones on mobile, you can use a plugin called &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/plugins/widget-logic/&#34;&gt;Widget Logic&lt;/a&gt;. It gives you a field on each widget to specify conditions on which to show it. Here you can tap into a cool Jetpack function to designate the widget to show up only on mobile. On the widgets you want to show on mobile devices, enter:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;jetpack_is_mobile()&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      For those widgets you only want on desktop, enter:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;pre&gt;!jetpack_is_mobile()&lt;/pre&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;alignnone wp-image-14072&#34; src=&#34;http://s2.mt-cdn.net/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/jetpackismobile.png&#34; alt=&#34;jetpackismobile&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; height=&#34;738&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      &amp;nbsp;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Further reading:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeremyfelt/Hooks-in-Jetpack&#34;&gt;A partial list of hooks in Jetpack&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jetpack.me/support/&#34;&gt;Official Jetpack documentation&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jetpack.me/support/jetpack-for-developers/&#34;&gt;Jetpack developers’ page&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jetpack.me/2013/06/27/customize-mobile-theme/&#34;&gt;Customizing the mobile theme&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;
      Hopefully, this will entice you to dig deeper into the capabilities of Jetpack. Have you done something cool with Jetpack? Share it in the comments!
    &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Does SSL Protect My Website?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2015 17:12:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/how-does-ssl-protect-my-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most economical and secure ways to protect your website on affordable hosting platforms is to deploy a private Secure Socket Layer (SSL) on you’re your website giving the instant ability to roll out protected URLs like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mysite.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.mysite.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are still in doubt as to what an SSL actually does consider this explanation from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.symantec.com/theme.jsp?themeid=how-ssl-works&#34;&gt;Symantec&lt;/a&gt; on the digital handshake that takes place between a browser and a server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A browser attempts to connect to a website secured with SSL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser requests that the web server identify itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends the browser a copy of its SSL certificate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The browser checks whether it trusts the SSL certificate. If so, it sends a message to the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The server sends back a digitally signed acknowledgement to start an SSL 7 encrypted session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encrypted data is shared between the browser and the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your site receives a permanent “security guard” which protects users in an online transaction, and encrypts data during transmission giving you, said Symantec, a “trillion year head start over a hacker.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“At current computing speeds, a hacker with the time, tools, and motivation to attack using brute force would require a trillion years to break into a session protected by an SGC-enabled certificate,” said Symantec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To enable strong encryption for the most site visitors, choose an SSL Certificate that enables 128-bit minimum encryption for 99.9 percent of website visitors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are other benefits, too, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credentials establish identity online&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication generates trust in credential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSL certificates on Intispace platforms are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed by Comodo, Geotrust, RapidSSL, Certum, Thawte, Symantec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;99.3% compatibility with browsers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;256-bit encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lock appears in browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shifting To An Encrypted Internet</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/shifting-to-an-encrypted-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 18:59:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/shifting-to-an-encrypted-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two thirds of all North American internet traffic will be encrypted by 2016, according to a new report by Sandvine, the Canadian-based software company. The reason behind it? Netflix.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1596&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to more and more sites using HTTPS encryption to protect confidential user information such as credit card numbers and other personal data, the days of having every website on the internet encrypted may not be far off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most visited sites is now making the switch to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/how-to-encrypt-everything-1586619248&#34;&gt;encrypted connection&lt;/a&gt;. Netflix has announced it will soon follow other internet giants such as Google and Amazon in making its services fully encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what is HTTP and HTTPS encryption?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) is the method by which files are transferred throughout the World Wide Web. This protocol determines how browsers and web servers send information back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTTPS adds protection to a typical HTTP. The additional ‘S’ is for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.westhost.com/blog/2015/02/11/what-is-ssl-and-do-i-need-it-for-my-site/#.VUuY6I5VhHw&#34;&gt;Secure Socket Layer (SSL)&lt;/a&gt;. This added layer encrypts all of the data that is sent between a browser and a server. In other words if a hacker were to look at the HTTPS-protected files being sent between a browser and a server, all they would see is lines of garbage code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This greatly protects a visitor if they’re submitting any personal information on a website. There is a trend of  some sites switching over to a HTTPS connection in order to up their level of security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know if the site you’re visiting is protected with SSL, take a look at the address bar. If you see a little green padlock or https:// before the web address, you’re on a site that is encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTPS around the web&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandvine &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sandvine.com/pr/2015/4/30/sandvine-two-thirds-of-north-american-internet-traffic-will-be-encrypted-in-2016.html&#34;&gt;conducted research showing that&lt;/a&gt; 65% of the internet’s current traffic is not encrypted. This will all change once Netflix makes the change later this year. One of the leaders in streaming services already accounts for about one third of North America’s internet traffic, meaning the change will make the majority of traffic encrypted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reed Hastings, CEO of Netflix, said, “[Netflix] is making the move to protect member privacy, particularly when the network is insecure, such as public WI-FI, and it helps protect members from eavesdropping by their ISP or employer, who may want to record our members’ viewing for other reasons.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a trend that most people predict will continue to grow. Google (including YouTube) already encrypts all of its pages, which accounts for a very large portion of the internet. Most e-commerce sites use HTTPS to protect their customers’ confidential information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CTO of Sandvine, Don Bowman, said, “The decision by leading applications to encrypt their traffic is great for subscribers because it ensures the content of their internet traffic remains private.”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect to see more business owners choosing to encrypt their sites. Although you generally have to pay a little extra for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/how-does-an-ssl-protect-my-website/&#34;&gt;SSL certificate,&lt;/a&gt; most agree that it’s well worth the price for the added protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great blog with SSL!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
