<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Seo on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/tags/seo/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 07:49:53 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEO 1001</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/04/seo-1001/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 07:49:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/04/seo-1001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;header&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;posted-by&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Where do you start with S.E.O?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/header&gt; &lt;section&gt;Yes, SEO. You’d be surprised how many people put it on their resume. After all, it’s just adding a heap of keywords into a webpage or blog post isn’t it? In a word. No. It’s not. Search Engine Optimization refers to a cosmos worth of rules and principles. What’s more, that cosmos is changing all the time.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;SEO guru Rand Fishkin, who founded The MOZ, defines the complexity of his field as follows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“SEO is any input that search engines use to rank pages. Anything that people or technology does to influence those elements is what the practice of SEO is all about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opens up all kinds of Pandora boxes. However, everyone has to start somewhere. Getting good at SEO begins with baby steps. Here are a few footsteps to follow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential S.E.O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tips are pretty much best-practice. These alone won’t get you the number one spot in the search engine rankings, but they will lay the foundations for the future…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Submission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step towards getting your website noticed by the search engines is to tell them about it. All the big search engines make it easy for you to submit your site to them. It takes less than 30 seconds for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/submit-url?pli=1&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com/toolbox/submit-site-url&#34;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawl Friendly Web Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web crawler is a computer program that search engines use to gather the data they need to rank a website in their listings. To make your website crawler-friendly you can do things like break up your web pages into chunks of copy with easily identifiable headlines for each section. It’s also helpful to upload a sitemap in XML format to your website. This will help crawlers navigate your site, especially if it’s a complex one. If you have pages on your website that you think might be misleading or irrelevant to a customer’s search aims, you can place a text file called robots.txt in the root of the website hierarchy. This will tell crawlers to disregard these pages. You can also use certain Google Webmaster tools to help identify crawl errors that could damage a site’s SEO ranking. Finally, try to avoid hiding important text in graphics, because crawlers can’t read this text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-2898 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/keywords-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;keywords&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research should help you get the right sort of visitors to your site. Keywords are the words that customers type into the search bar when they are looking for a service or product. Spending time researching these keywords can help your website appear in the search listings in relation to these keywords. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/what-google-exact-match-adword-changes-mean-for-your-business/&#34;&gt;Google Adwords&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool for figuring out the value of keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a good idea to do some research into the keywords your competition seem to be using – what keywords do they seem to be trying to use and what keywords do they rank well for? Plenty of tools exist to do this for you – just pop in the competitor’s URL and press go – all their secrets will be revealed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.seobook.com/general/keyword-density/%20&#34;&gt;SEO book&lt;/a&gt; is popular tool for doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research isn’t just something you need to do once. It’s a practice you need to keep updating constantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years Google has done everything in its power to stop people from cheating at SEO. Therefore, they’ve made it important for websites to feature quality relevant content. More specifically, content that is is expert and informative. Setting up a blog and using it to comment on relevant issues or to offer helpful advice can contribute to your content ticking the right boxes with the search engines. The mantra must alway be ‘make it useful for your visitors and do not focus on search engines and keywords’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Level SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got the basics sorted, you can try to make your website more competitive by following these tips…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engaging Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think you’ve written a masterpiece on your blog, but it doesn’t count for much if it’s not getting engagement. By this we mean social media shares and the encouragement of other websites and blogs to link to your work. Content is more likely to be shared if it solves a problem, raises an emotion, supports a cause, or offers an incentive for sharing. You can use free tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics/&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; to work out which pieces of your content are proving most popular with your visitors. In addition, you can use sites like Google Trends and Quora to get a better insight about what people are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again check out your competition to find out who is doing content really well in your market. Once you have found them check out what they are writing about and see what is getting the best shares and reader engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright wp-image-2899 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/SEO-links-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SEO links&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organic Link Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links are still a huge factor in website rankings. Anything that promotes link growth helps SEO. However, don’t be tempted to cheat at this, because Google has ways of blacklisting sites who do things like pay for links in shady places. You can increase the number of links to your site by forming relationships with bloggers and writing guests posts for them. As with any blogging activity, make sure what you write is bang on topic and useful for the audience. Pushing out the same lightweight piece and content with deep links and keywords will actually do you harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid any kind of automated or mass link building practices like blog comment spam, profile links, social bookmarking and article marketing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/guest-blogging/&#34;&gt;spam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting your content on social media can work wonders for your SEO. For example, studies have shown that content that is tweeted about a lot will be indexed by Google up to 50 percent faster than content that has not been put on social media. Social media is also a great place to get people talking about your brand,[&lt;header&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;posted-by&#34;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Where do you start with S.E.O?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/header&gt; &lt;section&gt;Yes, SEO. You’d be surprised how many people put it on their resume. After all, it’s just adding a heap of keywords into a webpage or blog post isn’t it? In a word. No. It’s not. Search Engine Optimization refers to a cosmos worth of rules and principles. What’s more, that cosmos is changing all the time.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;SEO guru Rand Fishkin, who founded The MOZ, defines the complexity of his field as follows…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“SEO is any input that search engines use to rank pages. Anything that people or technology does to influence those elements is what the practice of SEO is all about.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This opens up all kinds of Pandora boxes. However, everyone has to start somewhere. Getting good at SEO begins with baby steps. Here are a few footsteps to follow…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essential S.E.O&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tips are pretty much best-practice. These alone won’t get you the number one spot in the search engine rankings, but they will lay the foundations for the future…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Submission&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step towards getting your website noticed by the search engines is to tell them about it. All the big search engines make it easy for you to submit your site to them. It takes less than 30 seconds for both &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/submit-url?pli=1&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bing.com/toolbox/submit-site-url&#34;&gt;Bing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crawl Friendly Web Design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A web crawler is a computer program that search engines use to gather the data they need to rank a website in their listings. To make your website crawler-friendly you can do things like break up your web pages into chunks of copy with easily identifiable headlines for each section. It’s also helpful to upload a sitemap in XML format to your website. This will help crawlers navigate your site, especially if it’s a complex one. If you have pages on your website that you think might be misleading or irrelevant to a customer’s search aims, you can place a text file called robots.txt in the root of the website hierarchy. This will tell crawlers to disregard these pages. You can also use certain Google Webmaster tools to help identify crawl errors that could damage a site’s SEO ranking. Finally, try to avoid hiding important text in graphics, because crawlers can’t read this text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignleft wp-image-2898 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/keywords-300x199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;keywords&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;199&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyword Research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research should help you get the right sort of visitors to your site. Keywords are the words that customers type into the search bar when they are looking for a service or product. Spending time researching these keywords can help your website appear in the search listings in relation to these keywords. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/what-google-exact-match-adword-changes-mean-for-your-business/&#34;&gt;Google Adwords&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool for figuring out the value of keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a good idea to do some research into the keywords your competition seem to be using – what keywords do they seem to be trying to use and what keywords do they rank well for? Plenty of tools exist to do this for you – just pop in the competitor’s URL and press go – all their secrets will be revealed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.seobook.com/general/keyword-density/%20&#34;&gt;SEO book&lt;/a&gt; is popular tool for doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword research isn’t just something you need to do once. It’s a practice you need to keep updating constantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relevant Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years Google has done everything in its power to stop people from cheating at SEO. Therefore, they’ve made it important for websites to feature quality relevant content. More specifically, content that is is expert and informative. Setting up a blog and using it to comment on relevant issues or to offer helpful advice can contribute to your content ticking the right boxes with the search engines. The mantra must alway be ‘make it useful for your visitors and do not focus on search engines and keywords’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Level SEO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got the basics sorted, you can try to make your website more competitive by following these tips…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engaging Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think you’ve written a masterpiece on your blog, but it doesn’t count for much if it’s not getting engagement. By this we mean social media shares and the encouragement of other websites and blogs to link to your work. Content is more likely to be shared if it solves a problem, raises an emotion, supports a cause, or offers an incentive for sharing. You can use free tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/analytics/&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt; to work out which pieces of your content are proving most popular with your visitors. In addition, you can use sites like Google Trends and Quora to get a better insight about what people are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again check out your competition to find out who is doing content really well in your market. Once you have found them check out what they are writing about and see what is getting the best shares and reader engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignright wp-image-2899 size-medium&#34; src=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/SEO-links-300x300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;SEO links&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;300&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organic Link Building&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links are still a huge factor in website rankings. Anything that promotes link growth helps SEO. However, don’t be tempted to cheat at this, because Google has ways of blacklisting sites who do things like pay for links in shady places. You can increase the number of links to your site by forming relationships with bloggers and writing guests posts for them. As with any blogging activity, make sure what you write is bang on topic and useful for the audience. Pushing out the same lightweight piece and content with deep links and keywords will actually do you harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avoid any kind of automated or mass link building practices like blog comment spam, profile links, social bookmarking and article marketing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattcutts.com/blog/guest-blogging/&#34;&gt;spam&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Media&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting your content on social media can work wonders for your SEO. For example, studies have shown that content that is tweeted about a lot will be indexed by Google up to 50 percent faster than content that has not been put on social media. Social media is also a great place to get people talking about your brand,]&lt;a href=&#34;http://adage.com/article/media/google-s-schmidt-internet-cesspool-brands/131569/&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt; have said over and over again that branding is very important for ranking. If you build your brand visibility you’ll build your ranking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building your SEO requires marathon mentality rather than the race approach. It takes considerable time to see results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, you could always consider pay per click and display advertising to garner yourself some attention online. Display advertising is simply online advertising and it refers to things like banner ads and pay per click adverts. You need a bit of a budget to invest in this sort of advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do New gTLDs affect SEO?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/04/how-do-new-gtlds-affect-seo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 07:32:35 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/04/how-do-new-gtlds-affect-seo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New gTLDs are all the talk these days when it comes to domain names. However, how are these newly released gTLDs being treated by search engines such as Google?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the domain name business you can’t go even a few minutes without hearing all about gTLDs. Every business wants the ‘perfect’ domain name that will effectively brand its product or service, and recently many business have begun choosing gTLDs other than the traditional .com and .net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related to the topic of your ‘perfect’ domain name is SEO, or Search Engine Optimization. In other words, the one question every business owner wants answered is: how easily will potential clients find my website on Google and other popular search engines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a quick refresher, gTLD stands for generic Top Level Domain. This is the last part of your domain name after the meat of your URL. For example, .com is the most widely known gTLD, with .net and .org also very prevalent around the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re now noticing more and more gTLDs that are more synonymous with the rest of the domain name. For example, we’re now seeing .cash with finance websites, .ninja with, well, ninja websites, .guru for all those self-proclaimed experts, and hundreds more . These are part of &lt;a href=&#34;http://newgtlds.icann.org/en/&#34;&gt;ICANN’s new gTLD program&lt;/a&gt; which is releasing more and more new domain name extensions every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the frequently asked questions when it comes to new gTLDs is what effect will they have on SEO? Most businesses on the internet pay a lot of attention to their SEO. Many companies even hire SEO specialists in order to improve search engine results, so what are these SEO experts saying about new gTLDS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start with Google.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, Google insists a new gTLD will not affect search engine rankings as its algorithm is based on quality and popular content. “Crawlers” are still using sources such as links and meta data to display the best results for a search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/+MattCutts/posts/4VaWg4TMM5F&#34;&gt;Matt Cutts, leader of Google’s webspam team, said,&lt;/a&gt; “…as an engineer in the search quality team at Google, I feel the need to debunk this misconception. Google has a lot of experience in returning relevant web pages, regardless of of the top-level domain (TLD). Google will attempt to rank new TLDs appropriately, but I don’t expect a new TLD to get any kind of initial preference over .com, and I wouldn’t bet on that happening in the long-term either”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/+JohnMueller/posts/3wYuk1ca96z&#34;&gt;John Mueller from Google confirmed,&lt;/a&gt; “There still is no inherent ranking advantage to using the new TLDs. They can perform well in search, just like any other TLD can perform well in search”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can decide how much you trust Google’s response, but according to them, Google still displays the most relevant result to each search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the Moz Blog?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this research was conducted a number of years ago, the results tell us a lot about Google’s future with gTLDs. &lt;a href=&#34;http://moz.com/blog/are-exact-match-domains-in-decline&#34;&gt;SEOmoz showed that Exact-Match Domains&lt;/a&gt;, or EMDs, are declining in search engine results. In other words, search engines are displaying relevant results based on content much more than the actual domain name. EMDs were once considered the king of SEO, however it’s now apparent that this is declining with time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t to say that you shouldn’t buy a closely related domain name for your business. You should do that for branding purposes and to use with your marketing strategies. However, you can’t depend solely on your domain name to produce the absolute highest search engine results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relating this back to gTLDs, according to SEOmoz new gTLDs will have the same effect that a .com has on search engine results: that is, minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, this shows that content is king.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The domains.com says…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two reputable sources insist that gTLDs don’t affect SEO results, but try telling that to coffee.club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thedomains.com/2014/12/06/how-will-new-gtlds-rank-coffee-club-is-on-1st-page-of-google-1-a-week-after-launch/&#34;&gt;Thedomains.com noted&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;http://coffee.club/&#34;&gt;coffee.club&lt;/a&gt; jumped to the first page of Google search in only a week. Coffee.club has some stiff competition against closely related sites, yet has managed to find its way to the very top. In fact, at the time of writing, coffee.club is the very first result Google displays in the US when you search ‘coffee club’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could the gTLD .club be the reason for instant success?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEO expert searchmetrics.com’s study&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searchmetrics.com decided to take a more in-depth look at how new gTLDs might affect rankings. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.searchmetrics.com/de/2014/10/07/ranking-analyse-neuer-top-level-domains-berlin-tlds-in-der-lokalen-google-suche/&#34;&gt;The German SEO platform researched&lt;/a&gt; whether .berlin would position as well in search results as .com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research showed an obvious increase in results with .berlin. However, it should be noted that this research was done locally within a small demographic area. With that disclaimer, the results do show that .berlin domains had a significantly higher ranking than other extensions such as .com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local gTLDs such as .berlin and .london have shown significantly positive results. This proves credibility and shows the visitor that the site is specialized in a certain demographic area. When it comes to SEO a localized search may be classified entirely different than a broader search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reality, it’s a little too early to draw an absolute conclusion. Google claims that it won’t favor certain gTLDs, but other research shows that these new extensions are improving SEO. The way we see it is that a new gTLD may be a perfect fit for your business, but your sole reason for using one shouldn’t be for SEO purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now we suggest that you choose a domain name that will market your business best. To achieve the highest SEO rankings you will most likely want &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midphase.com/blog/seo-101/&#34;&gt;to stick to the basics&lt;/a&gt;: relatable and popular content will attract more and more visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, SEO remains to be a bit of a mystery that everyone wants to crack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Come Up With The Perfect Domain</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/03/how-to-come-up-with-the-perfect-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 07:37:23 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/03/how-to-come-up-with-the-perfect-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everyone is looking for the perfect name for a business. Do you know what makes a perfect domain name?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems pretty simple. All you need to do is come up with a catchy name for your business, throw a .com at the end of it, and behold, you have a perfect domain name for your up-and-coming reseller web hosting business! If only it were that easy…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A domain name should be simple. Think of all of the websites that you visit frequently: Google.com, php.net, facebook.com. All of these sites are very basic and easy to remember. This of course is ideal, but it can be difficult to be able to land the exact domain that you are after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People get into the web hosting reseller industry for various reasons. Web developers, for example, may want to offer web hosting services to their clients. This gives the developer the opportunity to market and sell all of the web services that a client will need (design, development, hosting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other resellers want to start their own small web hosting company to take advantage of the growing industry. Web hosting is a fast-paced field that increases as more and more websites are created every single day. Although the growth is predictable, that’s not to say that you don’t need to know how to market your business to have success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what the reason is for choosing to be a reseller, your new (or old but looking to be improved) business needs that perfect name. If you already have a perfect name for your business, go for it! Follow these simple steps and work on obtaining a perfect domain. If you are yet to come up with an original name for your reseller business, it may be a good idea to consider what your domain will be at the same time that you name your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many factors that contribute to the perfect domain name. We’ve come up with a few tips and tricks to come up with a domain that is easy for your customers to recognize, will work well from an SEO viewpoint, and will be convenient for you and your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are seven tips to keep in mind when coming up with a domain name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep it simple. &lt;/strong&gt;As mentioned before, you want to keep your domain name (and business’s name for that matter) as simple and short as possible. In today’s expanding world of business, that may not be as easy as it sounds. The key is to find that balance between having a creative name that sticks out to customers, but isn’t too difficult to remember. Avoid having too many words in your domain. One word is ideal, two is great, three is manageable, and anything more could be detrimental.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How about a hyphen? &lt;/strong&gt;Many people debate whether or not a hyphen is advantageous. From one point of view, it may give you a close alternative to the domain you want even though a competitor already has the actual domain you are after. The problem of having a hyphen in your domain is that it can disrupt SEO results and can also confuse a potential client. He or she may end up at your competitor’s site rather than your own. There are occasions when a hyphen may be your only choice, but avoid using them if at all possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternate versions. &lt;/strong&gt;If the domain name you want is unavailable, you may need to settle for something similar, such as adding the word “the” or making your name plural. However, if you’re going to tweak your domain just a bit, such as making it “theexamplewebdesign.com” rather than “examplewebdesign.com,” make sure to market your business as The Example Web Design. Otherwise, your clients may get confused and go to the wrong site. Again, do everything possible to keep your domain name and business name identical.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid words that are hard to spell. &lt;/strong&gt;Try not to include words that may be hard for clients to spell. Consider looking at this list of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://grammar.yourdictionary.com/spelling-and-word-lists/misspelled.html&#34;&gt;100 most misspelled words&lt;/a&gt; in the English language. If one of these words is in your anticipated domain name, it is worth reconsidering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be descriptive. &lt;/strong&gt;Although some of the largest technology companies in the world don’t have descriptive names, e.g. Samsung and Apple, your aspiring business does not have the same background as these technological giants. If you’re in web design, make it apparent. If you’re starting a blogging as business, let it be known. There’s no mistaking that &lt;a href=&#34;http://intispace.com&#34;&gt;Intispace.com&lt;/a&gt; specializes in web development. Give your business the advantage by telling potential clients exactly what it is you have to offer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLD. &lt;/strong&gt;Choosing a TLD, or Top-Level Domain, can be tricky but very beneficial if done right. (Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com/2015/03/a-glance-of-top-level-domains-and-subdomains/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a detailed description of TLDs.) A few years ago, it was a no-brainer to try and snag a .com TLD for any business. Now, hundreds of new and unique TLDs are being released to account for the growth of online business. If the .com domain that you’re looking for is already taken, consider exploring new options. The newly released TLDs are becoming more and more popular and may provide your business with the distinction that you’re looking for. Some sensible options for resellers are .graphics, .business, and .services. Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://newgtlds.icann.org/en/program-status/delegated-strings&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to find the most up-to-date list of gTLDs that ICANN has released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t hesitate.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have an idea for a domain name, don’t wait around to purchase it. Domain names go quick and you never want to miss out by only a couple of months while you’re finalizing your business plans. Purchase the domain first, then take care of other details. If you have a couple of ideas for domain names, it’s worth buying both.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult (and unrealistic at times) to be able to follow &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of these guidelines. However, do everything you can to come up with a simple domain name that describes your business well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not in the web development industry, consider applying these same tips to find a perfect domain name for whatever industry you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reselling web hosting and domains is an exciting opportunity that can open doors to clients all over the world. When done correctly, reselling web hosting – whether as a package with other services or just the web hosting alone – can be a very profitable business. Keep checking the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.intispace.com&#34;&gt;intispace blog&lt;/a&gt; for more upcoming tips on starting your own business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, send us a tweet &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/intispace&#34;&gt;@intispace&lt;/a&gt; with your own ideas on what makes a great domain name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
