<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Dns on Muhammad Fahrizal Rahman </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://riesal.github.io/tags/dns/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 01 May 2015 02:23:33 &#43;0000</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is The Status Of Your Domain?</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-is-the-status-of-your-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 02:23:33 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/05/what-is-the-status-of-your-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failing to renew your domain name can have costly consequences. Read below about two cases of failed domain name renewals and what you can do to prevent the same from happening to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more-1423&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most instances purchasing a domain name is not as literal as you may think. In fact, it would be more accurate to say that you’re &lt;em&gt;leasing&lt;/em&gt; a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally when you buy a domain name you have the option of how long you’d like to keep it. Most domain registrars will give you the option between one and ten years. This gives you the flexibility to decide how long you’ll need the domain name. When the time is up you are given the option to renew your domain name in order to keep your business online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there is the all too common case of forgetting to renew a domain name. This can be detrimental to a business, sometimes leading to a dreaded rebranding. In extreme cases, a business may entirely crumble due to the loss of its domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://motherboard.vice.com/read/activists-turned-an-anti-gay-politicians-website-into-an-lgbt-resource&#34;&gt;Recently, an Idaho state representative&lt;/a&gt; experienced the hassle of losing his domain name. Paul Shepherd, the Idaho Republican, forgot to renew his domain &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulshepherdusa.com/&#34;&gt;www.paulshepherdusa.com&lt;/a&gt;. 21-year old college junior Dylan Hailey noticed that the domain name was expiring soon and jumped on buying it as soon as he could. Hailey turned his newly acquired domain into a website to expose Shepherd’s anti-gay policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hailey did make it known that he would give Shepherd his site back, but under the condition that he makes a donation to the LGBT rights group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shepherd isn’t the first to fail to renew a domain name. Last year, Sony Online Entertainment fell victim to the same process, this time letting their sonyonline.net domain expire. This led to putting thousands of gamers out of commission, causing angry protests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sony apologized, stating, “DNS issues may take up to 48 hours to resolve. We are really really sorry on this one folks. Embarrassing and preventable. We screwed up”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you prevent this from happening to you? Here are some easy tips to follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up automatic renewal.&lt;/strong&gt; This will renew your domain, leaving you to focus on more important matters. However, make sure your credit card details are up to date, otherwise your domain registrar will have no way of billing you automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update your contact information.&lt;/strong&gt; Your registrar will most likely contact you when your domain is about to expire (Resell.biz will do this 30 days prior to the expiration date). Having a current email on record means you will always be kept informed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay attention if your domain does expire.&lt;/strong&gt; If you do by chance let your domain expire, you should be given a grace period of 30 days, during which you can still renew your domain. Once the grace period is over, you’ll have a short redemption phase (typically around 30 days, but this can vary depending on the top level registrar). You can still renew your domain during this time, but it will cost a hefty fee. After the redemption phase, your domain will be back on the market, available to anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renew your domain name for the appropriate amount of time.&lt;/strong&gt; Most registrars allow you to register a domain from anywhere between one and ten years. If you are purchasing a domain that will be vital to your business’s success, we suggest registering it for the maximum amount of time. If you do take this route, make sure you don’t forget to register your domain name seven years down the road!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t fall victim to an expired domain name. Check the status of your domain name by contacting your registrar today. So, What is The Status Of Your Domain ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://intispace.com/contact-us&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intispace.com support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;if you have any questions regarding domain name renewal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; Note: &lt;a href=&#34;http://intispace.com&#34;&gt;Intispace.com&lt;/a&gt; clients can check and renew their domain by accessing control panel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glance of Top-Level Domains And Subdomains</title>
      <link>https://riesal.github.io/2015/03/a-glance-of-top-level-domains-and-subdomains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 07:43:50 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://riesal.github.io/2015/03/a-glance-of-top-level-domains-and-subdomains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A perfect domain name may be just what you and your clients need. Take a look at what exactly TLDs and Subdomains are and what they can do for your business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently wrote a post about the behind-the-scenes details of DNS. In that post, I went through how your browser finds the web page you’re looking for by simply typing in a domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A domain is the unique name/title of your website. It’s what your clients will associate with your business. Apple.com, for example, is the domain name for the dominant computer company, Apple. Seems pretty obvious, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want your business and your clients’ business to have the absolute best domain for whatever you or your clients might be selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’re in the food catering industry. Catering.com seems like the perfect fit, right? The problem here of course is that there can only be one catering.com in the entire world. A company already owns the domain catering.com and has it registered. For the time being, no other business can use food.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for you, there are numerous options available for a relevant domain for your catering business. To understand the different routes you can take to find the perfect domain, we first need to understand the difference between top-level domains (TLDs), second-level domains and subdomains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DNS functions as a hierarchy: it begins with the top-level domain, followed by the second-level domain, then finally, the subdomain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Level Domain (TLD)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TLD is the last word or sequence of letters in a domain. Some of the most recognized TLDs are .com, .uk, .net, .org and .edu. Under the direction of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icann.org/&#34;&gt;ICANN&lt;/a&gt;, each TLD is registered by a specific organization. ICANN breaks down all TLDs into four separate categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generic top-level domains (gTLD).&lt;/strong&gt; These domains are the most recognizable, with .com, .org, .edu and so on. Before 2014, there were only 22 different gTLDs. Now, ICANN has released 100s of domains, including some as radical as .ninja and .hiphop. The reason behind this is that as the internet grows, domains will become harder and harder to obtain. New TLDs give aspiring businesses the opportunity to have a relevant domain name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Country code top-level domains (ccTLD).&lt;/strong&gt; Country Code TLDs are operated privately and are specifically designated for particular countries. They are reserved to serve communities. The ccTLDs are made up of two letters. Some common examples are .us, .uk, .cn and .au.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internationalized country code top-level domains.&lt;/strong&gt; These domains are similar to the ccTLDs, but are geared more towards countries that use the Arabic alphabet or non-alphabetic writing systems such as Japanese. An example is  &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D9%85%D8%B5%D8%B1.&#34;&gt;مصر&lt;/a&gt;, which is reserved for Egypt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure top-level domain.&lt;/strong&gt; This group consists of only one domain, the Address and Routing Parameter Area (ARPA). It is used exclusively for technical infrastructure purposes. This TLD is simply .arpa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can register a domain with many different companies, but all eventually link back to ICANN to form a database of all TLDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second-Level Domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second-level domains are like the core of a domain name in that it is directly below the top-level domain. The second-level domain is generally associated with the organization that is registered to the domain name. If we look at the domain,&lt;a href=&#34;http://intispace.com&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;, “intispace” is the second-level domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subdomain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A subdomain is exactly what is sounds like: a domain that is part of a larger domain. Subdomains are read from left to right and are separated by dots. We commonly see this with email. For example, mail.google.com will take you to your Gmail account. Another common example of a subdomain is if there are separate divisions within an organization or business, such as support.example.com or finance.example.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subdomains should not be confused with subdirectories. Subdirectories are files and folders that are part of a domain, such as resell.biz/domain-reseller/. The part of the domain: /domain-reseller/ is a file of resell.biz, not a subdomain. Subdomains always come before the TLD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.catering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have explored the different parts of a domain name, we can go back to our example of a catering business and find a perfect domain name. Within ICANN is a department called Internet Assigned Numbers Authority, or IANA. IANA focuses on maintaining the codes and numbering systems involved with the internet. The IANA keeps a Root Zone Database that contains all of the gTLDs available. You can find the list &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iana.org/domains/root/db&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conveniently enough, .catering is an available TLD. We can now move forward and include the second-level domain: the name of the business. For our example, we’ll choose the name “Logan Valley.” A perfect domain name would be loganvalley.catering. We can check the availability of this domain by searching on virtually any domain name reseller’s website. I went to &lt;a href=&#34;https://panel.intispace.com/&#34;&gt;panel.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;, to search the availability of slipi.catering. You can test your future domain by clicking &lt;a href=&#34;http://panel.intispace.com/domain-registration/index.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for this example, loganvalley.catering is (at time of writing) available. You can purchase the domain and web hosting services, design your website, and have your online business up and running in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your business grows, you may want to add subdomains. You could add a sales.loganvalley.catering, services.loganvalley.catering and info.loganvalley.catering. These subdomains will all function under the domain name loganvalley.catering. Subdomains are generally easy to set up once you own the domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although domain names now may seem more complicated than just your business’s name plus a .com, it really is easy to find the perfect domain for you. Explore different options. If you want to stick with a .com TLD you may need to adjust your second-level domain just a bit. We suggest looking into new TLDs that will help boost your business. A unique domain name may just be what your business needs to really take off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article was brought to you by Intispace Netmedia, for scalable wordpress hosting visit our site here &lt;a href=&#34;https://intispace.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;www.intispace.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
